<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xml:base="https://example.com/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Longform Articles</title>
    <link>https://example.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://example.com/feed/long.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>A collection of longform articles.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Season One Finale</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/2022-11-02-season-one-finale/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fsof1.jpeg&amp;width=1140&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 1140w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fsof1.jpeg&amp;width=1140&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 1140w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fsof1.jpeg&amp;width=1140&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;Trip map&quot; width=&quot;1140&quot; height=&quot;773&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Day 14: Hong Kong, 2,461 steps, 2.1 kilometers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always always &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; plan for at least one rest day at home after a trip. Don’t jump back to work right after you return. The comfort of that one “buffer” day is impossible to overestimate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Especially if it was a long and/or physically taxing trip. This one was both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And to be honest, I should’ve planned for at least two days of rest and recovery. But capitalism calls…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;310,250 steps, 253.2 kilometers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hadn’t planned for this much walking. &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com/posts/tranquility-peace-calm-pamper/&quot;&gt;My goal&lt;/a&gt; was to beat 10 kilometers each day — so I expected to finish this trip with somewhere around 150 km.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A peculiar pattern emerged. Every night I went to bed completely spent. &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com/posts/banged-up/&quot;&gt;Used up&lt;/a&gt;. Come morning, legs wanted to move again. First few kilometers felt like I was gliding. Almost effortless. &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com/posts/the-one-last-pizza-toast/&quot;&gt;The body&lt;/a&gt; was longing for traversal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s all done now. And it feels good. It feels like an accomplishment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But of course, it’s not just about the distance. It’s about the things I’ve seen and been able to appreciate (by the virtue of passing by them s l o w l y, not just giving them a brief glimpse from a window of a taxi). And it’s about the people I was able to meet and talk with. Yeah, cliche as it sounds — &lt;em&gt;the real treasure was the friends I made along the way&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, “friends” is overselling it — but I’m so grateful for each piece of human connection, however small, I was able to make across these 13 days. For all the openness and kindness I experienced &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com/posts/it-feels-different/&quot;&gt;from day one&lt;/a&gt;. Profound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4 pizza toasts, countless coffees, teas, meals, and snacks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the food, how can I not mention the food (and everything food-related)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, kissa coffee is its own thing. I knew what to expect. But I also had some divine cups along the way. Pour-over Honduras at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.weekenderscoffee.com/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;Weekenders Coffee in Kyoto&lt;/a&gt; was definitely a highlight. Tea-like flavor, almost as if it was a gesha varietal. But it wasn&#39;t! Very enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the time I ate at low-to-medium-priced places. With a &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com/posts/banged-up/&quot;&gt;couple&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com/posts/the-one-last-pizza-toast/&quot;&gt;exceptions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each meal so memorable. Kaiseki dinner at Hoshinoya Karuizawa, omakase sushi set at Sushiiwa Kyoto, akitendon at Dontoya (worth an &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com/posts/population-66123/&quot;&gt;extra stop&lt;/a&gt; in itself), omakase tempura at Sakui, and the godly bowl of ramen at Menshu Takenaka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each city, &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com/posts/population-66123/&quot;&gt;however small&lt;/a&gt;, having so much to offer. I walked the hell out of some of them and yet, it still feels I’ve only scratched the surface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it’s good. A trip like that should make you feel wanting more. You should leave each city before you overstay your welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the pizza toast? I can’t say I have reached &lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.specialprojects.jp/products/kissa-by-kissa-3rd-ed?variant=40722736480411&amp;amp;ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;Craig Mod’s level of worship&lt;/a&gt; for it, but I will certainly miss it. Thank goodness we can have pizza toast at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fsof2.jpg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fsof2.jpg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fsof2.jpg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;We have pizza toast at home&quot; width=&quot;2000&quot; height=&quot;1333&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;8,584 words, 2,102 shutter clicks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am truly proud of the creative rigor I imposed onto myself. Like, I know it’s not a lot of output if you just look at the numbers. A few hundred words and less than a dozen pictures published each evening — I’ve seen &lt;em&gt;single&lt;/em&gt; blog posts amounting to more than this newsletter&#39;s grand total.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But making myself comb through 100-200 pictures, cull them, edit the selected ones, and weave a short story around them &lt;em&gt;every evening&lt;/em&gt; was no small thing. It was test of willpower and discipline I had to pass every night. And to pass it, sacrifices big and small had to be made every night (no evening YouTube for you, Chris).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I’m so happy I did it! Even if just a handful of people read it, it was worth it. It made me &lt;em&gt;make&lt;/em&gt; something again. Put something (and myself) out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having this newsletter and these pictures will make my memories of this trip richer, I’m sure of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1 backpack, 1 camera, 1 lens&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What made it all work, and made it all possible, was my commitment to one bag travel. Just me and one backpack. Every piece of clothing, every piece of gear had to fit in there or in my pockets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What an exercise in trimming everything down to just the essentials. And what freedom and flexibility (unexpected stops, day trips) it enables!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fsof3.jpg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fsof3.jpg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fsof3.jpg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;Gear shot&quot; width=&quot;2000&quot; height=&quot;2667&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Packing solutions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The core packing solution was my Peak Design Everyday Backpack Zip 20L. Inside — one of each: medium (for clothes) and small (underwear) packing cube. Early into the trip, a small dopp kit fit inside as well — later to be replaced with a bag of souvenirs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Side pockets — filled with the dopp kit on one side, and a Field Pouch (holding cables and chargers and other miscellany) one the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the left shoulder strap, a small karabiner with Peak Design Cuff attached to it and a Capture Clip — that’s where I would stow my camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the last minute purchase — the Everyday Hip Belt I got in Ginza on my second day. Transformative. Took some weight off my shoulders and that has contributed to my travel and walking comfort tremendously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point was to make it all modular. I get to the hotel, I take the packing cubes and pouches out — and the backpack transforms from a travel pack to a daypack. Easy and quick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from that, I had another Field Pouch with a strap and Capture Clip that served as a sling back on lighter days (or days with more predictable weather) and as an extra personal item for flights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clothes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Two Outlier t-shirts, two Arc’teryx t-shirts, Arc’teryx long sleeve, Mont-bell long sleeve, Outlier pants, Suitsupply “traveler” shirt (for &amp;quot;work&amp;quot; day in Tokyo), Arc’teryx Sigma pants, Underarmour Storm Jacket, Y3 zip-up hoodie, merino underwear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It worked magnificently. I’m an Arc’teryx believer from here on out. (Outlier less so.) This kit has gotten me through a highly variable Japan autumn weather. Temperatures ranged from 1° to mid-20s Celsius. Conditions from drizzle, to rain, to all out sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With only so many changes of clothes I was able to pack, I had to account for at least one laundry run in the middle of the trip. I packed a laundry detergent and made sure all my clothes were fast-drying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Camera&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Leica M11 with Summicron 28 mm. A perfect travel companion. Limiting myself to just one lens, and it being a 28 mm focal length, made it feel almost like a Q2. But I do appreciate the flexibility in changing the lenses back at home (my go-to is 50 mm Summilux), the USB-C port, and the opportunity to learn how to operate a rangefinder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my first trip with this camera. And I have to say, I took some of my favorite pictures ever in the past two weeks. Are they my &lt;em&gt;best&lt;/em&gt; pictures? On a technical level, likely not — some are slightly out of focus (very easy error to make with this sensor), for some I was too slow to capture the right moment, and some do show my slight discomfort with lens this wide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the memories those pictures carry — priceless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the photos in this series (except for the ones in this single post) were taken with that kit. Most of the time shot wide-open at ƒ/2. All edited in mobile Lightroom (with &lt;em&gt;maybe&lt;/em&gt; a handful receiving one extra touch-up in Apple’s Photos app).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The camera itself and the experience of using it deserve a separate article (Leica M11 Field Test?). It’s not without flaws — some being intentional limitations you might want to impose onto yourself (limitations breed creativity, after all), others just being small annoyances — but overall, I loved it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Computing &amp;amp; accessories&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My main computing device was the latest iPad mini (2021) — combined with Microsoft’s Foldable Keyboard (my favorite mobile typing experience, sadly — discontinued), and Apple Pencil 2nd gen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worked flawlessly for editing photos in mobile Lightroom, writing up the newsletters in iA Writer, reading books and watching Andor and Peripheral on the flights and train rides. It’s perfect for travel. Not too big, super-light, modular, competent, fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When out and about — iPhone 13 Pro + Apple/Google Maps + Apple Watch Series 8 (Apple Maps on the Watch was a great help on my walks).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AirPods Pro, chargers, MagSafe battery pack, and necessary cables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No need for anything more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Miscellaneous&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Prescription medicine, COVID tests, lens cleaning tissues, hand cream, shaver, dopp kit, laundry detergent, neck buff, extra camera battery (not used once), SD card reader dongle, Allen key, and a few more bits and bobs I’m now forgetting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that’s my entire packing list. Like I said — just the essentials. Most importantly, nothing from this list failed on me. Everything performed as expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prioritize reliability and you’ll be fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Prep work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did not over-prepare. I don’t think? Though my wife mercilessly mocked me for trial-packing a week in advance. So I don’t know. You tell me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important piece of preparation was to figure out the logistics. The flights (including making a decision where to start the trip and where to end it — am I making a loop or an point A-to-B kind of trip?), the cities along the way and how they connect (are there convenient train connections? what kind of JR pass would I need, if any at all?), and hotels in each city. This part also included double-checking COVID-related restrictions on the way out and the way back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second most important part was deciding how and what to pack. The result you’ve probably already read above. This covered researching the weather and watching and re-watching Craig Mod’s packing livestreams. And ultimately buying the missing pieces of gear (which turned out to be a lot).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And lastly — researching what to see and where to go in each city. &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://craigmod.com/ridgeline/132/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;Tiny Barber, Post Office&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; newsletters for Matsumoto and Tsuruga were extremely helpful with that. But I marked maybe two or three key places in each city, not more. Left everything else to serendipity and luck (of which I apparently ran out in Kyoto, but it was fun nonetheless).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what about the language? Yeah, the language barrier was there. Most of the conversation I had were superficial, an awkward mix of clunky English and Japanese, with &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com/posts/in-search-of-nodoguro/&quot;&gt;some&lt;/a&gt; almost entirely through Google Translate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you definitely can make this trip without knowing any Japanese (I mean, at least learn some basic pleasantries). You just need to accept (concede?) that you will miss out on some things, lack some context, won’t be able to go deep enough. But it’s still going to be a fantastic experience. Don’t let the language stop you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me thank three people who made this trip and this newsletter possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My wife, Ingrid. She entertained my idea of a solo trip and let me go with it. Encouraged it, even. We’re taking turns traveling – one person always has to stay back and take care of our CKD cat. And our cat is &lt;em&gt;a lot of work&lt;/em&gt;. I&#39;m not exaggerating. Ingrid, I appreciate your effort so much.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://craigmod.com/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;Craig Mod&lt;/a&gt;. For basically handing me a blueprint for this trip and this newsletter. Heaps of advice. Packing livestreams, walk livestreams, walk newsletters, books, travel-to-Japan tips, and more. Read and re-read and multiple times over.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.powoli.blog/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;Miłosz Bolechowski&lt;/a&gt;. For prompting me to write the first entry and encouraging me with kind words along the way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for all the support and encouragement. Thank you thank you thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What’s next&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that concludes this trip. &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com/s01/&quot;&gt;Season one. The Hokuriku Arch.&lt;/a&gt; I will keep this site and this newsletter alive — let&#39;s say the show has been renewed for the second season. No release date yet, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There might be quick intermissions, short notes, I’ll send out from here from time to time. You can also find me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/ksobny/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ksobny?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for following along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Chris&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Your Name</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/2022-11-02-season-one-finale/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Last Pizza Toast</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/2022-11-01-one-last-pizza-toast/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Folpt1.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Folpt1.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Folpt1.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;Pizza toast&quot; width=&quot;2000&quot; height=&quot;1500&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Day 13: Kyoto, Hong Kong, 13,297 steps, 10.9 kilometers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Programming note: In my &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com/posts/the-uji-excursion/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;last entry&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; I had anticipated that this one is going to be shorter. Instead, it’s regular-length, but late. I hope that’s okay?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I search Google Maps for 喫茶店 one last time. Doing that around 7:30 am with “open now” filter applied should get me the result I want (I’ve noticed coffee chains and third-wave coffee shops here usually don’t open until 9-11-ish am).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there it is! Coffee Amazon, about a 20-minute walk from the hotel. And it has pizza toast on the menu. Jackpot!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I walk through the drizzle, covering my camera from the rain with my jacket (give me better weather sealing, Leica!) — I take it out only to take pictures of people carrying transparent umbrellas. I want to catch that signature (cliche?) Japan picture. I mostly fail — my rangefinder focusing skills are still no match for moving subjects (partly because lack of skill, partly because I stubbornly insist to shoot at wide apertures). I settle for static objects instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Folpt2.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Folpt2.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Folpt2.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;Rainy Kyoto&quot; width=&quot;2000&quot; height=&quot;1500&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Running on fumes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While walking to Coffee Amazon I realize I’ve passed the 250-kilometer mark on my way. Well, less &lt;em&gt;realize&lt;/em&gt; — more like I&#39;m counting down the meters. 250 clicks — no small feat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I can tell. The &lt;em&gt;body&lt;/em&gt; is exhausted, but &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; feel good! &lt;a href=&quot;https://craigmod.com/ridgeline/149/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;“Few things feel better than the body [many] days into a good long walk.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s weird, though. The legs are tired, but they want to keep moving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I arrive, get my usual &lt;em&gt;morning set,&lt;/em&gt; and chat a bit with the lady running the establishment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been two weeks. And this is my last &lt;em&gt;kissaten&lt;/em&gt;, last pizza toast in Japan. I linger more than usual, just to cherish that moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I eventually leave, the lady bids me farewell saying “Be careful in Hong Kong.” Feels sad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Folpt3.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Folpt3.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Folpt3.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;Coffee Amazon&quot; width=&quot;2000&quot; height=&quot;1500&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lunch makes me walk even more. I want to end my stay in Kyoto on a high note. Like, with a meal that leaves a lasting impression (of a good kind). Omakase sushi is my choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the first restaurant I visit, they say they’re not open for lunch today and they will only be serving dinner. (Google Maps and their website say they’re open for lunch. Whatever.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second restaurant says they only accept guests with reservations. Heck, was I aiming too high? — should I settle for a more down-to-earth meal? Why is this so hard?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rain is getting worse. Giving it one last try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third restaurant. Sushiiwa. I’m greeted with a question “Reservation?”. “No.” I say resigned — but they don’t send me away right away. “Wait a moment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You’re lucky. Please sit at the counter.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader, what happened next was my best restaurant experience in Kyoto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Toshiya-san introduces himself as the chef and owner. He speaks perfect English. He notices my camera and recommends I visit the Leica Store in Gion — apparently, apart from the cameras, they have a great photo exhibition there. (Too bad I won’t have time for that today.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The man exudes warmth. He’s so welcoming and &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; chatty. Over the next hour, he stops at my seat multiple times — not just to serve the food, but to continue our conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talk about his business. Third generation running it. Started by his father 65 years ago just a few blocks from where we are now. Today, Toshiya-san owns it, and his daughter is working there as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Folpt4.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Folpt4.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Folpt4.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;The Ohnishi family running Sushiiwa&quot; width=&quot;2000&quot; height=&quot;1500&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last three years have been tough. Business went down 70% — Japan was closed to tourists. He said the restaurant was only able to survive because he owns the building. Whole family lives upstairs. Had he had to pay rent to a landlord, he would’ve gone bust for sure. Many other restaurants in the area have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But October 11th, 2022 was like flipping a switch. Everything is suddenly back in full force. Floodgates are open, tourists are pouring in. He’s fully booked on most days (he reiterates how lucky I am to be able to get a walk-in seat today). It’s bit of a shock for him and the staff to have to adjust to being this busy again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Food comes at a steady pace. A few appetizers, fantastic sashimi!, soup, and eight pieces of sushi served one by one. He brings my attention to the soy sauce. “This is Kyoto-style soy sauce, different from Tokyo-style” — he says — “Less salty, milder, and sweeter.” I learned something new today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smile’s not leaving my face throughout the entire meal. So happy I found this place! Being turned out by the first two restaurants today was no bad luck at all. On the contrary! It allowed me to discover this establishment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thoroughly enjoyed the food, the welcoming atmosphere, and the chat. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sushiiwa.jp/en/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;Sushiiwa&lt;/a&gt; — I highly recommend it! Please check it out if you’re ever in the Kyoto Station area. (You might need to make a reservation!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Kyoto Station — that’s where I go next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tadaima!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here, it’s all just the way home. I board the Hello Kitty-themed train to the airport. I get on a KIX-HKG flight. Gets uncomfortably bumpy in the last hour — we’re flying through a typhoon that’s over Hong Kong right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Folpt5.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Folpt5.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Folpt5.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;Hello Kitty train&quot; width=&quot;2000&quot; height=&quot;1500&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inbound passenger processing at Hong Kong International Airport is surprisingly smooth — it took about 40 minutes from disembarking the plane to getting on AirPort Express. So much better than 4+ hours I had to endure on my way back from Poland last year (not to mention the lack of hotel quarantine this time around).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Folpt6.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Folpt6.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Folpt6.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;Welcome home&quot; width=&quot;2000&quot; height=&quot;1500&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more taxi ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then it’s 9:50 pm HKT on a Tuesday. I’m back home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Another programming note: There will be one more entry in this series. After I get some rest?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Chris&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Your Name</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/2022-11-01-one-last-pizza-toast/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Uji Excursion</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/2022-10-31-the-uji-excursion/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Ftue1.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Ftue1.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Ftue1.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;Uji&quot; width=&quot;2000&quot; height=&quot;1125&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Day 12: Kyoto, Uji, 35,482 steps, 28.5 kilometers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of tea was had today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But before that, let me check off one more item from &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com/posts/avoid-kyoto-he-said/&quot;&gt;my Kyoto list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Ftue2.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Ftue2.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Ftue2.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;Saga-Arashiyama, The Bamboo Forest&quot; width=&quot;2000&quot; height=&quot;1500&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Matcha Town&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uji. Just a 30-minute train ride form Kyoto Station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Renown for its tea and widely considered to produce the highest grade of matcha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love how Uji has built its identity around this green powder. You see it everywhere. It’s in drinks, soba noodles, ice cream, candy, sweets, gyoza, ramen, dango… I’m not kidding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Ftue5.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Ftue5.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Ftue5.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;Uji&quot; width=&quot;2000&quot; height=&quot;1500&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course, you can smell it in the air too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can get over-caffeinated really quickly here. Simply can’t avoid having green tea in one form or another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But one would be wrong to assume that matcha is the only thing that Uji has to offer. Oh, there’s more! Temples! Shrines! Historic bridges! Scenic views!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What really got me was the combination of autumn colors (ginkgo leaves just getting yellow!), the river, and the red bridges. Spent good few minutes just sitting there and admiring the view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Ftue3.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Ftue3.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Ftue3.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;Uji&quot; width=&quot;2000&quot; height=&quot;1500&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the evening, I just aimlessly walked around the streets of Kyoto.Unfamiliar just two days ago — today, navigated with much more ease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s my last night here. In Kyoto. In Japan. LOTS of feelings. This trip has challenged me physically (walking) and mentally (embracing the unknown, leaning on serendipity, talking to strangers, traveling solo…). It’s been intense — but in a good way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Ftue4.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Ftue4.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Ftue4.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;Kyoto&quot; width=&quot;2000&quot; height=&quot;1500&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will post a proper summary some other time. But for now, I’m excited to go back home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programming note: tomorrow’s entry will likely be on the shorter side. I will be spending most of my day in transit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good night, good night, good night…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Chris&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Your Name</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/2022-10-31-the-uji-excursion/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Avoid Kyoto, He Said</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/2022-10-30-avoid-kyoto-he-said/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fakhs1.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fakhs1.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fakhs1.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;Kyoto&quot; width=&quot;2000&quot; height=&quot;1328&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Day 11: Kyoto, 34,780 steps, 28.2 kilometers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello from Kyoto!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big city energy here, most definitely. Everything’s more densely packed. Hotels on top of inns on top of ryokans. Coffee chains and franchise restaurants. Shopping malls. Tour buses parked in front of every major landmark. Crowds. Traffic. Rush.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a contrast! From &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com/posts/population-66123/&quot;&gt;population 66,123&lt;/a&gt; to 1.5 million. And in a couple of days, back home, it will be 7.5 million (&lt;a href=&quot;https://hongkongfp.com/2022/08/12/over-113000-residents-left-city-in-12-months-as-hong-kong-sees-largest-mid-year-population-drop-on-record/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;but shrinking&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In planning my trip, I tried to adhere to Kevin Kelly’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/Zz70rcguxwk?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;excellent advice&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On vacation go to the most remote place on your itinerary first, bypassing the cities. You’ll maximize the shock of otherness in the remote, and then later you’ll welcome the familiar comforts of a city on the way back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like… almost. Kind of failed the first part, with &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com/posts/it-feels-different/&quot;&gt;my starting point being Tokyo&lt;/a&gt;. But does it really count if I was there only for a moment and partly for work? The &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; trip &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com/posts/friday-night-good-time/&quot;&gt;started in Matsumoto&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now, in Kyoto, I’m being eased back into &lt;em&gt;big city life&lt;/em&gt;. And at the same time, I&#39;m failing to follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://craigmod.com/ridgeline/147/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;Craig’s suggestion&lt;/a&gt; to avoid this city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tourist traps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Craig’s right, though. Kyoto for sure is feeling the brunt of tourism. Today, I woke up at 5:30 am only to be able to take pictures of the Fushimi Inari Shrine gates without any people getting into the frame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fakhs2.jpeg&amp;width=1600&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 1600w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fakhs2.jpeg&amp;width=1600&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 1600w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fakhs2.jpeg&amp;width=1600&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;Red gates&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tourists everywhere!&lt;/em&gt; — complained the tourist. Well, you have only yourself to blame, don&#39;t you — if you’re stuck in traffic, you &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; the traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I visited a few &lt;em&gt;postcard spots&lt;/em&gt; today, with a couple or so still left on my list. Will likely tick them off tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that’s the thing about my stay in Kyoto. So much more than in other cities, this one feels like going through a to-do list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or maybe it’s not Kyoto’s fault. Maybe it’s my non-vacation habits slowly creeping in as my trip comes to an end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fakhs3.jpeg&amp;width=1600&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 1600w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fakhs3.jpeg&amp;width=1600&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 1600w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fakhs3.jpeg&amp;width=1600&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;Hokan-ji at 7:56 am&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;2134&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, it’s not all just postcards and landmarks and school trips and couples taking (pre-)wedding photos. If you look hard enough, there are hidden gems to be found — like this coffee shop on Teramachi-dori, Mahayana.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside, just one U-shaped counter. Ten seats around it. In the middle of everything — the store’s owner. He’s probably in his 80s, or thereabouts. His customers are not much younger, either. This feels like one of the shrinking number of places where I still can significantly bring down the age average just by showing up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The air is thick with cigarette smoke. &lt;em&gt;All&lt;/em&gt; of the customers at the counter are either smoking or vaping. And all of them seem to be regulars — they chat with each other, and with the owner, like a group of old friends. Seems about right — the board on the wall is overflowing with coffee tickets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fakhs4.jpeg&amp;width=1600&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 1600w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fakhs4.jpeg&amp;width=1600&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 1600w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fakhs4.jpeg&amp;width=1600&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;Mahayana&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The owner is an absolute gentleman. He tries to chat with me a few times, despite me not understanding a word he says. Still tries (and succeeds) to make me feel welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s near closing time and everyone just got a free refill of coffee from whatever was left in the siphon. Come 5:30 pm, one of the customers(!) flips the sign on the door — from &lt;em&gt;Open&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;Closed&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I leave, grab some dinner, and crawl back to my hotel room. I’m completely exhausted. Covered most ground in one day today in this entire trip. Time to rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fakhs5.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fakhs5.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fakhs5.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;Kyoto&quot; width=&quot;2000&quot; height=&quot;1500&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s see what hidden gems I can find tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goooood night!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Chris&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Your Name</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/2022-10-30-avoid-kyoto-he-said/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Population 66,123</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/2022-10-29-population-66213/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fpop66k1.jpeg&amp;width=1140&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 1140w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fpop66k1.jpeg&amp;width=1140&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 1140w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fpop66k1.jpeg&amp;width=1140&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;Tsuruga&quot; width=&quot;1140&quot; height=&quot;757&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Day 10: Kanazawa, Tsuruga, and my final station, 21,174 steps, 17.5 kilometers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made an executive decision to add one extra stop on my way today. How spontaneous! Adventurous!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Hello from Tsuruga!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A tiny port town, surrounded by mountains from three sides and bay from the fourth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The moment I stepped off the train I knew something was different. The air was crisp, breezy — and the wind was carrying the smell of the sea, fish, and… cement? Right… the cement factory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tsuruga is another town I learned about from the &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://craigmod.com/ridgeline/132/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;Tiny Barber, Post Office&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; newsletter. And when I looked at the map yesterday — there it was, on the way to my final city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan crystallized. And it included lunch and a short hike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I arrived at Dontoya, the benches around the shop were full of hungry people waiting for their turn. I claimed my place in line and waited patiently with others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patience was very much required. Time from getting the ticket to sinking my teeth in crispy batter: 69 minutes (nice!) Long! — but was it worth it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hell yeah! Behold — this thing of beauty: Akitendon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fpop66k2.jpeg&amp;width=1600&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 1600w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fpop66k2.jpeg&amp;width=1600&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 1600w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fpop66k2.jpeg&amp;width=1600&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;Akitendon&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aki&lt;/em&gt; — autumn. &lt;em&gt;Tendon&lt;/em&gt; — assorted tempura on top of a bowl of rice. Seasonal special — how could I not. Full of autumn vegetables, mushroom, and fish. The bowl was so packed, that they included additional small plate so you can put some items aside while you enjoy your tempura with rice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Satisfaction from the meal to time waited ratio: off the charts. It was spectacular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up: a hike up the hill overlooking the bay and the cement factory. You reach the observation point and learn everything you need to know about why the air smells the way it does here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fpop66k3.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fpop66k3.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 2000w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fpop66k3.jpeg&amp;width=2000&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;Tsuruga cement factory&quot; width=&quot;2000&quot; height=&quot;1328&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more hour on the train, and here I am. The last city. The final stop. The end of this nearly two week long trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finish the day in an izakaya. Quite difficult to find and a good distance away from the congested tourist routes. Enjoying multiple advantages of my choice this evening: no queue, quaint, homey atmosphere, great food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nobilitas is run by a couple, a husband and A wife. Clear division of duties — the husband cooks, and the wife takes the orders and manages the money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those two have great chemistry — laughing off each other jokes (I don’t understand the jokes, but I understand the laughs), exchanging meaningful looks — seems like they&#39;re having fun?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it’s a family-run shop, smoking inside is allowed. I don’t linger. I settle the bill as soon as I finish the food. And before my clothes absorb the cigarette smoke’s smell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I start exploring this city for real. Setting my alarm for very early morning right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fpop66k4.jpeg&amp;width=1600&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 1600w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fpop66k4.jpeg&amp;width=1600&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 1600w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=src%2Fassets%2Fimages%2Fpop66k4.jpeg&amp;width=1600&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;Kyoto&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;2133&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good night!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Chris&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Your Name</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/2022-10-29-population-66213/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>