<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xml:base="https://metagame.hk/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Metagame | Full Feed</title>
    <link>https://metagame.hk/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://metagame.hk/feed/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Blog about photography, tech, gaming, coffee, travel, and personal productivity.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>2025-05-10 20:57</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-10-2057/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;POSSE test 2&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 20:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-10-2057/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025-05-10 10:21</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-10-1021/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think I have a working prototype of my static-HTML blog ready? It looks decent! Lightweight, just the essential stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I just need to go through the process of transfering my 30 blog posts from Ghost to here. Will be a while! I&#39;ll consider it my weekend project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 10:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-10-1021/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025-05-08 19:46</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-08-1946/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vibe-coding my way through setting up a static HTML blog on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.11ty.dev&quot;&gt;11ty&lt;/a&gt;. I have time until October to migrate away from Ghost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now how do I publish this on GitHub pages? Oh my!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 19:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-08-1946/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Is the Year of Linux on Desktop</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-04-this-is-the-year-of-linux-on-desktop/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a restless mind. I constantly look for ways to tinker with stuff. And once something works, I can&#39;t just leave it be and enjoy it. I have to move on to something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-03-31-is-apple-even-good-at-software/&quot;&gt;Last month&lt;/a&gt; it was (re-)introducing pen and paper to my note-taking system. Before that, it was the &lt;a href=&quot;https://metagame.hk/posts/2024-12-15-things-look-like-a-creative-goty/&quot;&gt;back-and-forth between Reminders and Things&lt;/a&gt; for my to-do system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you can imagine how dangerous &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/pVI_smLgTY0?si=BmXPv3MjrxTFV14Z&amp;amp;ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; is for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;s&gt;What’s stopping me right now is&lt;/s&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://frame.work/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;&lt;s&gt;Framework Laptops&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;s&gt;not shipping to Hong Kong…&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually installed Ubuntu on my gaming laptop today, alongside existing Windows 11 installation. Just to try it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m sure I won&#39;t get far. I&#39;ll probably encounter some insurmountable barrier and give up. I will inevitably bump into some jankiness, critical apps with outdated design (looking at you, Libre Office), or things simply not working (as I write this I struggle to make my external monitor to work!) I just hope that some big disappointment happens before I manage to spend any extra money to plug Linux into my workflow. Because I would have to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restart my 1Password subscription for a cross-platform password manager (currently with Apple Passwords)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move my email from iCloud back to Fastmail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable Obsidian sync, since my notes would no longer sync over iCloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find a new to-do app (Tick Tick looks like a decent candidate)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Probably subscribe to Spotify instead of Apple Music (or give YouTube Music another try?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming I stick with YouTube for #5, which at the moment doesn&#39;t cost me anything beyond what I&#39;m already paying, items 1-4 still add up to USD 215 per year. That is not insignificant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there&#39;s the cost of time required for setting everything up (though, let&#39;s be honest, that&#39;s the fun part) and moving my to-do&#39;s to some new app (switching mission-critical apps, assuming you even find a suitable replacement, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ljpuk.net/2025/05/04/tasks-out-of-sight-dont-get-done/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;can be a headache&lt;/a&gt;!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, there&#39;s the sunk/opportunity cost in under-using (or not using at all) the devices I already own, primarily my iPad Pro and Mac mini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when I think about that last one – it raises the biggest question of all. Linux would primarily replace MacOS for me. But then, Mac is the only platform Apple has not fully locked down yet. So why even try to escape it now? With Mac, I don&#39;t have the same frustrations Windows users have. There is less incentive to switch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I can do is to lay the groundwork for eventually leaving Apple&#39;s lock-in. A decision I&#39;m inching closer and closer to every time Apple does something greedy, malicious, or when it ingratiates itself with Trump. Which is very often these days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-04-this-is-the-year-of-linux-on-desktop/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025-05-08 12:00</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-04-1200/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 Is a Masterpiece.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since a piece of art enamored me so completely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m in love with this game. World, characters, story, visuals, gameplay, soundtrack — enchanting, captivating, unique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hype is real. Believe the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.metacritic.com/game/clair-obscur-expedition-33/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;high metacritic scores&lt;/a&gt;, trust all the positive reviews. This game is special. It deserves the reverence it’s been met with so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can sing its praises for many more paragraphs, but let me stop here. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedition33.com/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;Just go and play it&lt;/a&gt;. The less say about it the better — it’s best to go in blind.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-04-1200/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Lot Less Excited About Nintendo Switch 2 Than I Thought</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-04-03-a-lot-less-excited-about-nintendo-switch-2/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/docs/lmkFOzxwC9-1140.avif 1140w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/docs/lmkFOzxwC9-1140.webp 1140w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://metagame.hk/docs/lmkFOzxwC9-1140.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Nintendo Switch 2&quot; width=&quot;1140&quot; height=&quot;641&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Nintendo Switch 2 / Image: Nintendo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I genuinely wanted to be excited about &lt;strong&gt;Switch 2&lt;/strong&gt; (it was my most anticipated hardware announcement this year!), yet – if I&#39;m being honest with myself – it just looks like a bad buy for me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#39;ve barely touched my Switch OLED since I bought it. (A painful realization!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fromsoftware.jp/duskbloods/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;The Duskbloods&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; console-exclusive, that initially looked like it would scratch my &lt;em&gt;Bloodborne 2&lt;/em&gt; itch – turns out it&#39;s a PvPvE game! No, thanks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&#39;t have any strong feelings or nostalgia for &lt;em&gt;Donkey Kong, Mario Kart,&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Kirby&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything else, including &lt;em&gt;Hollow Knight: Silksong&lt;/em&gt;, will be available on PC, it will look A LOT better there, and I already have Steam Deck OLED to play those games on the go (and with OLED!)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hollow Knight&lt;/em&gt; with its art style in particular – I expect it to look much better on OLED compared to LCD.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other than that, the third party games looked really poor. I know Switch isn&#39;t about high-end specs and cutting-edge graphics, but that&#39;s really not an excuse for releasing a game that looks like &lt;em&gt;Pokemon Legends Z-A&lt;/em&gt; in 2025.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prices, both hardware and games, are high enough to give me pause.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaking of prices, the fact they’re charging for their equivalent of &lt;em&gt;Astro’s Playroom&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Aperture Desk Job&lt;/em&gt; is such an own goal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I expected something that would bring me back to the Switch — but last night&#39;s Nintendo Direct wasn&#39;t it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, whatever excitement I had about it initially is now fading. Maybe I was just hyped for an &lt;em&gt;idea&lt;/em&gt; of a shiny new thing. Once I set emotions aside, Switch 2 doesn&#39;t look like a device for me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-04-03-a-lot-less-excited-about-nintendo-switch-2/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blogging Like It&#39;s 2015</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-04-03-blogging-like-its-2015/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following up on my thoughts from &lt;a href=&quot;https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-03-31-is-apple-even-good-at-software/&quot;&gt;the previous post&lt;/a&gt; — I&#39;ll. be publishing shorter entries here. For a while — as an experiment. They would not go into the newsletter initially – instead they would wait their turn for the next monthly newsletter bundle-edition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s a bit of a manual process in Ghost, but I&#39;ll roll with it for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#39;ll have less pressure and more flexibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can still follow the blog in &lt;em&gt;real-time&lt;/em&gt; through RSS or social media links (I&#39;ll be cross-posting them using &lt;a href=&quot;https://openvibe.social/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;Openvibe&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your inbox won&#39;t get spammed with multiple short post newsletters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you still prefer to receive updates via email, monthly newsletter edition will do just that&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds like a worthwhile experiment to me! If it works out, it will encourage me to introduce more improvements (moving from Ghost to static pages, closer integration with the federated web, automating the newsletter digest, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it&#39;s the bubble I follow, but I&#39;m seeing a trend of &lt;a href=&quot;https://jasonsantamaria.com/blog/once-again-from-the-top?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;returning to&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://ljpuk.net/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;small-scale&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://lmnt.me/blog/make-a-damn-website.html?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;personal&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://rknight.me/blog/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;blogs&lt;/a&gt; and withdrawing from social media. Owning what you create instead of feeding it into the algorithm. Tinkering with your own website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was passionate about this format 10-ish years ago (I used to have a small-but-award-winning personal finance blog) — hope I can find this feeling again, here and now. This experiment with shorter but more frequent posts is a step in that direction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-04-03-blogging-like-its-2015/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Apple Even Good at Software?</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-03-31-is-apple-even-good-at-software/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/docs/PBIUJEbbmt-1140.avif 1140w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/docs/PBIUJEbbmt-1140.webp 1140w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://metagame.hk/docs/PBIUJEbbmt-1140.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;New pen day!&quot; width=&quot;1140&quot; height=&quot;855&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;em&gt;New pen day!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today’s entry is a mix of various topics. Each of the headlines below could’ve been its own tiny blog post, but since this is a blog &lt;em&gt;and a newsletter&lt;/em&gt;, I feel this pressure of not spamming your inboxes with tiny stuff — whatever I send out needs to be substantial. So I bundle these things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s actually something I need to think about. Sometimes I want the freedom of just firing off a short post over here. I like that format! Especially since I don’t really post on social media anymore, so this page could be a nice outlet for small updates like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Need to look into Ghost options — or maybe consider migrating to static pages (11ty?) and building my website around that? An ideal outcome would be some kind of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.citationneeded.news/posse/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;POSSE solution&lt;/a&gt; with a (monthly?) newsletter digest getting compiled in the background. Hold that thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, this is what I’ve got:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New Pen Day!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I have sunk in deeply into a new hobby — fountain pens and related stationery (notebooks, in particular).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we lived our lives mostly offline, online was an escape from the real world. But now more and more we live our lives online. And this time the real world becomes an escape — from notifications, distractions, predatory monetization, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here I am, researching fountain pens, notebooks, pen loops, modded iPods, and trying to find an excuse to get into film photography again. But let’s stick to stationery for now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like having another thing in life to &lt;em&gt;figure out&lt;/em&gt;. Another area to explore. Something new. I’m just worried it will be superficial, that my handwritten journaling will be mostly writing about writing. Running around in circles like that. I have fallen into that trap before, with my “note-taking” node in Obsidian having the most linked-to notes at one point. I’m worried that I will focus on the tools and not the process. That I will write ideas down, sure, but then do nothing with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there is some doubt among all this excitement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But for now, I’m having fun. Enjoying the morning ritual of journaling in my notebook, the nib gliding on the paper, and leaving a trace of ink with nice shading. And it’s one more way in which I can use my iPhone less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;But No New Bag Day&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peak Design’s Kickstarter campaign for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/peak-design/roller-pro-carry-on-luggage-by-peak-design?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;the new carry-on suitcase&lt;/a&gt; is live, after LOTS of teasing. Looking at the price, specs, and reviews this one is a &lt;em&gt;skip&lt;/em&gt; for me. 4 kilograms for a carry-on, are you kidding me? This is a very US-specific product. It’s (literally) not going to fly here in Asia, where most of the airlines have 7 kgs limits for carry-ons. Oh well, that’s $500 &lt;s&gt;saved&lt;/s&gt; not spent. And my &lt;em&gt;no new bags in 2025&lt;/em&gt; commitment for this year can stay safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Smartphone Best Practices&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But rolling back to using my iPhone less… I have been inspired/moved by this article from Miłosz Bolechowski: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.powoli.blog/o-higienie-uzywania-smartfona/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;o higienie używania smartfona&lt;/a&gt; (beware! – it&#39;s in Polish and behind a paywall). TLDR: the more you disconnect, the more you get done, the fuller your days are, the more meaningful your conversations are. Smartphone should not be a constant companion in everything we do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My approach: I consider the phone as a utility toolkit. It’s for giving me access to bank apps, passwords, photo import &amp;amp; editing apps, notes, maps, and communication. I limit notifications (including badges) to the critical and time-sensitive ones. Only non-algorithm entertainment is allowed: RSS, books, music, podcasts. No social media, no YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s working out so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, my iPad is a different story. What I limit on the iPhone, I often (over-)compensate with my tablet usage. As a next step, I’ll need to tackle that somehow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For what it’s worth, my early mornings are now device-free. Just coffee, pen, and paper. Feels good. Feels pure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;99% Pure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of interesting reads — another article that made an impression on me recently was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.joanwestenberg.com/on-ideological-purity/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;On Ideological Purity&lt;/a&gt; by Joan Westenberg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s the thing: I try to make thoughtful purchasing choices — not only in making sure that the products I buy will fit my life/needs well, but also aiming to support good/ethical businesses. Voting with my wallet. Thing is, it’s not always easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I left Twitter, Facebook, and Threads, I’m avoiding Amazon (them &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/news/612898/amazon-removing-kindle-book-download-transfer-usb?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;turning off book downloads&lt;/a&gt; was the final straw), I try to support local businesses in Hong Kong (especially those that supported the local community in trying times), I don’t give Google analytics about Metagame’s readers, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I also give my money to Apple — begrudgingly, even though I’m trying to avoid making big tech CEOs even richer. I’m increasingly disappointed by their choices, tech-related and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/3/24335290/apple-donation-donald-trump-inauguration-tim-cook?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;others&lt;/a&gt;, yet I will likely buy something in the Apple Store this September. And I will occasionally buy something from Amazon, if I can’t get it elsewhere. I still sometimes use Instagram, WhatsApp, and Messenger. And there are many other examples where my spending (be it money or time/attention) doesn’t exactly align with my values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to feel guilty about it. &lt;em&gt;If I’m not 100% pure in my choices, then what is even the point?&lt;/em&gt; But Joan’s article beat some sense back into me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t have to be 100% perfect in my anti-capitalist, anti-corporate, anti-US/big-tech choices. As long as I’m mindful, act with intention, and doing my best, doing &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; — that’s enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perfection is not the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Is Apple Good At Software?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of begrudging Apple and things being imperfect, I&#39;ve been feeling negative about that company for a while. They keep giving me reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/news/629940/apple-siri-robby-walker-delayed-ai-features?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;Apple Intelligence is a joke&lt;/a&gt;. The only remotely useful thing it was supposed to offer got delayed indefinitely. Passwords app was prone to an &lt;a href=&quot;https://9to5mac.com/2025/03/18/apples-passwords-app-was-vulnerable-to-phishing-attacks-for-nearly-three-months-after-launch/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;embarrassing vulnerability&lt;/a&gt; for months. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macstories.net/stories/not-an-ipad-pro-review/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;iPad is still a baby computer&lt;/a&gt;; hardware generations ahead of its software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is just a sample from the last few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tend to bounce between &lt;a href=&quot;https://metagame.hk/posts/2024-08-13-ios-18-public-beta-personal-computing-tools-audit/&quot;&gt;going all-in on Apple’s apps&lt;/a&gt;, prioritizing ecosystem integration — and, on the other end of the spectrum — replacing Apple’s solutions with third-party apps, looking for ones that are best in class. Sometimes, I’ll add extra difficulty by searching for apps that are &lt;a href=&quot;https://ljpuk.net/2025/03/27/a-move-to-cross-platform-apps-and-services/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;cross-platform&lt;/a&gt;. A classic dilemma between a jack-of-all-trades approach and best-in-breed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple will cover all the basics with Reminders, Notes, Journal, etc. — but it’s rarely going to be the best solution in each slot. Their apps will get infrequent updates (at best once a year between WWDC and new iPhone release; at worst - forgotten/becoming an afterthought, like Clips or Journal). Always two steps behind the industry trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, third party apps still innovate. To me and for my needs, Fantastical is a better calendar app than Apple Calendar. 1Password is a better password manager than Apple Passwords. Day One is a better journaling app than Apple Journal. Things is a better to-do app than Apple Reminders. Notes — here I’m having a hard time finding a 1-to-1 replacement. Obsidian may be better for PKM stuff and long-term storage, but short-term quick capture is not its best suit (but hey, pen and paper exists!). But then, you lose some benefits of deep integration with the OS and some money as well (as most of the best third party apps out there require a subscription these days).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what good is system integration if the biggest benefit, integrating information across various apps in your account and making personalized suggestions based on that, Apple promises — but can’t ship?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I feel like I will never solve this dilemma. Every choice is a trade-off. It&#39;s becoming easier, though, because more and more Apple and its solutions seem to be offering less and less (relative to competition).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a feeling that my next &lt;a href=&quot;https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-01-09-default-apps-for-2025/&quot;&gt;default apps list&lt;/a&gt; will have fewer Apple apps on it. Unless, of course, next WWDC wows me in a big way this June (which seems unlikely?)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 24:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-03-31-is-apple-even-good-at-software/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I’ve Been Using Apple Mail All Wrong</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-01-30-ive-been-using-apple-mail-all-wrong/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/docs/eAYvuuPthJ-1140.avif 1140w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/docs/eAYvuuPthJ-1140.webp 1140w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://metagame.hk/docs/eAYvuuPthJ-1140.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Apple Mail Cake for my wife&quot; width=&quot;1140&quot; height=&quot;855&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Apple Mail Cake for my wife&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple Mail doesn’t like us, &lt;em&gt;inbox-zero&lt;/em&gt; people. And I have realized that only just now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see, until recently, my personal email management followed what I did at work. Basically, keeping the inbox clear by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;filing messages to various folders (like “Travel”, “Newsletters”, and “Paper Trail”) — some manually, some using email rules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;archiving messages that I no longer need quick access to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deleting one-time codes, magic links, and other one-time-use messages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But with iOS 18.2, Apple rolled out automated email categories in iPhone’s Mail app — and I was like &lt;em&gt;Wait a minute…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The email categorization only works in the Inbox. Messages don’t carry their categories/labels with them if you move them elsewhere, be it a folder or Archive. It’s not account-wide, it just applies to one single folder and that folder is the Inbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;…am I supposed to be keeping all my emails in the Inbox?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signs have been there before — default smart folders like “today”, “unread”, or “attachments” also only work on emails that are in your inbox folder. Archive it or move it anywhere else — they won’t get picked up anymore. Huh…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links to messages (like when you drag an email from Mail to Notes) also &lt;em&gt;sometimes&lt;/em&gt; stop working if you move emails between folders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now we have those “AI” email categories. Limited to Inbox once again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay Apple, I’ll give it a go. I’ll keep my emails in the Inbox. (This is going very much against my GTD habit of regularly reviewing my inboxes and clearing them out — but I’m willing to experiment with a new workflow!) Will this automated categorization work better than a curated list of folders and email rules? Color me skeptical — especially after &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macstories.net/reviews/apples-commitment-to-ai-is-clear-but-its-execution-is-uneven/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;seeing&lt;/a&gt; what other parts of Apple Intelligence had to offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and I think I owe you all an explanation of what is up with this hero image! It’s a cake I had custom made to celebrate my wife’s email inbox reaching 50K unread emails. Turns out she had it all figured out long ago!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fast forward two weeks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, this post has been sitting in &lt;em&gt;drafts&lt;/em&gt; for a while… But it’s a good thing! I can now report on the results of this experiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long story short: I will probably disable it. Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/docs/e8vIUEjIqi-1121.avif 1121w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/docs/e8vIUEjIqi-1121.webp 1121w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://metagame.hk/docs/e8vIUEjIqi-1121.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of a notification summary&quot; width=&quot;1121&quot; height=&quot;458&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;em&gt;AI got that one right…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The categories don’t fit my needs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-hk/guide/iphone/iphfe4a36baf/ios?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;Apple describes&lt;/a&gt; these four automated categories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Primary:&lt;/em&gt; Find personal messages and time-sensitive information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transactions:&lt;/em&gt; Keep track of your confirmations, receipts, and shipping notices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updates:&lt;/em&gt; Catch up on news, newsletters, and social updates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Promotions:&lt;/em&gt; Browse your coupon and sales emails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That doesn’t work for me. It’s too broad and not mutually exclusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too broad, because a category like &lt;em&gt;Transactions&lt;/em&gt; holds travel bookings, invoices, shipping notifications, and updates from my bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not mutually exclusive, because there is significant overlap between categories. This makes me unsure where to look for a specific email — making finding emails easier, not more difficult, was the whole point of this feature!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, my bank sends me a range of messages: login notifications, transaction notices (are these updates? transactions?), promotional emails (updates or promotions?), and occasional financial literacy newsletters (updates or promotions?) — Apple Intelligence has trouble sorting this out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is restaurant booking confirmation and update or a transaction?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/docs/aCjcqmGh4u-1170.avif 1170w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/docs/aCjcqmGh4u-1170.webp 1170w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://metagame.hk/docs/aCjcqmGh4u-1170.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Gas bill wrongly categorized as promotional email&quot; width=&quot;1170&quot; height=&quot;526&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Apparently, my gas bill is a “promotion”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Same with annoying online shops, where they will send you a purchase confirmation and immediately follow up with a latest issue of their newsletter (and is that a transaction, update, or promotion? — Apple Mail is not sure)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This all make the categories unreliable for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;It’s still buggy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, notification labels at the top will retain their little notification dot even though there are no new or unread emails there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But it’s a beta, of course there are bugs!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not a beta if you’re rolling it out to all users on a &lt;em&gt;public&lt;/em&gt; release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The rollout is annoying&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been weeks and the feature remains iPhone-exclusive. Does Apple think that rushing it out, before it’s ready on all platforms, will increase adoption?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my case, if I can’t have one, consistent system across all my devices/email clients, then it’s not going to work for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;It’s poorly explained&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/docs/-Pz5A-BvF1-1170.avif 1170w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/docs/-Pz5A-BvF1-1170.webp 1170w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://metagame.hk/docs/-Pz5A-BvF1-1170.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot from Apple Mail&quot; width=&quot;1170&quot; height=&quot;787&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Screenshot from Apple Mail&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen people confused about what this new yellow button means. Is it &lt;em&gt;mute&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;block sender&lt;/em&gt;? Crossed-out person icon would suggest something like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But no, it’s just means “hide from &lt;em&gt;primary&lt;/em&gt; category” and applies to non-primary emails, that Apple thought were time-sensitive and deserve being ”promoted” to &lt;em&gt;primary&lt;/em&gt;. But isn’t it what &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-hk/guide/iphone/iph9ae667055/ios?ref=metagame.hk#:~:text=View%20Priority%20Messages%20in%20your%20inbox&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Priority Messages&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was for? Sigh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Full inbox is not for me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And lastly, just a personal preference, but I really do like my inboxes being empty rather than full.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this entire Apple Intelligence rollout has cured me from a feature-FOMO. I don’t have to be using the newest thing Apple came up with, just because it’s new and shiny and has an “AI” label. I’m fine with my own workflow, thank you very much. Additional benefit — less pressure to upgrade my devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, what I want is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; for AI to make decisions for me. I want features that help me make &lt;em&gt;better&lt;/em&gt; decisions — easier, faster, and with better hit rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that is to say that I’d prefer more powerful and accessible tools for setting up iCloud email rules, because &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/iCloud/comments/18afxy8/managing_icloud_mail_server_rules_now_possible/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; is bullshit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 24:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-01-30-ive-been-using-apple-mail-all-wrong/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 Likes and Dislikes</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-01-20-2024-likes-and-dislikes/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the best pieces of advice I’ve found on Tim Cain’s channel was about finding reviewers that you can trust. It’s not always easy, especially in the age of companies either sponsoring content outright or sending &lt;em&gt;innocent&lt;/em&gt; freebies to YouTubers and other influencers. Whose opinions should then carry most weight in your own decision-making?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t remember the particular video, so I’ll just link to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@CainOnGames?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;Tim’s channel’s home page&lt;/a&gt;. It’s well worth your time! (And I know it‘s not the first time I’m recommending it here — it’s just that good!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, back to that specific advice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go through their review archive and see if they liked the games/shows/movies/etc. that you liked. In other words, &lt;strong&gt;seek out people with taste similar to your own&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It sounds so obvious now, but it’s not something I had been paying close attention to before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help you see whether METAGAME aligns with your interests and taste, here’s a list of various media that I liked and disliked in 2024. (A word of caution, this may look a lot like those #promosky posts on BlueSky — you’ve been warned!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Games&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;I liked&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pacific Drive:&lt;/strong&gt; Loved the atmosphere and their take on &lt;em&gt;Roadside Picnic&lt;/em&gt; trope. Where STALKER 2 underdelivered, this one made up for it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God of War (+ Ragnarok):&lt;/strong&gt; In late 2024, I was going through my PlayStation backlog. I really enjoyed the story and characters in GoW.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Destiny 2: The Final Shape:&lt;/strong&gt; Destiny 2 ended the 10-year saga on a high note. Enjoyed everything from the campaign to the final raid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Black Myth: Wukong:&lt;/strong&gt; A souls-like where I felt like the difficulty was perfectly tuned for my late-30s reflexes. Plus, it was a big thing here in Asia and I enjoyed discussing boss tactics with friends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;I disliked&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anything &lt;strong&gt;Destiny 2&lt;/strong&gt; that came after The Final Shape: The episode format was a miss for me. The story, the direction, and pretty much all the news coming out from Bungie in 2024 – all bad. I eventually abandoned the game completely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diablo 4: Vessel of Hatred:&lt;/strong&gt; Have I aged out of ARPGs or was Diablo 4 expansion just not good? The new class was fine, but I just can’t find anything enjoyable about the gameplay, seasonal format, or the story.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Meh&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;STALKER 2:&lt;/strong&gt; I’ll wait until it’s patched and playable on my system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Path of Exile 2:&lt;/strong&gt; Another case of aging out of the genre.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Music I Liked&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;St. Vincent - All Born Screaming:&lt;/strong&gt; Never been a fan of St. Vincent. I discovered her latest album in preparation for Clockenflap music festival in Hong Kong. And it was a revelation. “Reckless” was on repeat in my Music app for a long time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pacific Drive - Original Soundtrack:&lt;/strong&gt; It low-key slaps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;autoplay *; encrypted-media *; fullscreen *; clipboard-write&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:660px;overflow:hidden;border-radius:10px;&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-forms allow-popups allow-same-origin allow-scripts allow-storage-access-by-user-activation allow-top-navigation-by-user-activation&quot; src=&quot;https://embed.music.apple.com/hk/album/pacific-drive-original-soundtrack/1745066550?l=en-GB&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Shows&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;I liked&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slow Horses:&lt;/strong&gt; Gary Oldman just kills it in this quirky spy thriller.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shogun:&lt;/strong&gt; Speaking of killing it, Anna Sawai and Hiroyuki Sanada in &lt;em&gt;Shogun&lt;/em&gt; — stellar performances. And the cherry on top with all the anjin-translation memes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Penguin:&lt;/strong&gt; And of course Colin Farrell as Penguin. And Cristin Milioti — what a scene-stealer! Lots of great performances this year!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;X-Men ’97:&lt;/strong&gt; Came for nostalgia, stayed for impactful storytelling and social commentary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Star Trek: Lower Decks:&lt;/strong&gt; Final season aired in 2024. I will miss these characters dearly! If you’re into Star Trek but dismissed Lower Decks because it’s a “silly cartoon” — you’re missing out. It’s much more than that. (FWIW, I like it SO MUCH more than &lt;em&gt;Discovery&lt;/em&gt; and I strongly believe it’s a better Trek than &lt;em&gt;Disco&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;I disliked&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunny:&lt;/strong&gt; Did not do it for me at all. All the intrigue and mystery from the first episode(s) went nowhere. There was no payoff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Silo (season 2):&lt;/strong&gt; Just a slog. Barely anything happens. And once it does, chances are the scene is so dark, you can’t see a thing anyway!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dune: Prophecy:&lt;/strong&gt; While I love Dune (it’s one of the most important books I’ve read in my life!), this series felt like a mediocre fan-fic to me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Movies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;I liked&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dune: Part 2:&lt;/strong&gt; The movie, on the other hand, totally delivered. Visited the cinema multiple times!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alien: Romulus:&lt;/strong&gt; Story was interesting, visuals were fantastic, callbacks to previous installments were nice and not too much. And Cailee Spaeny was just marvelous as the lead for the movie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;I disliked&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deadpool &amp;amp; Wolverine:&lt;/strong&gt; Same deal as with Diablo 4. Am I aging out of this genre or is Marvel just not good anymore?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Books&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;I liked&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oliver Burkeman - Meditations for Mortals:&lt;/strong&gt; A more humane take on productivity wrapped in pondering on mortality. Took lots of notes from this one!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Apps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;I like&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Things:&lt;/strong&gt; For a to-do app, it just works the way my brain works.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes:&lt;/strong&gt; Simple, uncomplicated, supports typing and handwriting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;I dislike&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notion:&lt;/strong&gt; Clunky, bloated, slow, and trying to do too much.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Craft:&lt;/strong&gt; Same as above but add frustrating navigation to the mix.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Can’t make up my mind&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obsidian:&lt;/strong&gt; I love the principles it’s built around, don’t love the execution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So… how’s it looking? Do our tastes align?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;BTS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2024 I started being more diligent about writing my thoughts on various pieces of media that I watch/read/play. And being more systematic about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this, I use a simple tagging system in Apple Notes. If anyone asks me for recommendations, I can access that information easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/docs/Z5EHH-sbEG-1206.avif 1206w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/docs/Z5EHH-sbEG-1206.webp 1206w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://metagame.hk/docs/Z5EHH-sbEG-1206.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tag filtering in Apple Notes to show highly rated books from 2024&quot; width=&quot;1206&quot; height=&quot;808&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Tag filtering in Apple Notes to show highly rated books from 2024&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do that for all sorts of things. I’m keeping track of restaurants the similar way (helps when deciding where to eat), coffee (what beans to reorder from what roasters), and other products I buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would’ve been easier, more seamless, and automated to do that in Obsidian with the Dataview plugin, but Apple Notes does a good enough of a job for me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 24:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-01-20-2024-likes-and-dislikes/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>