<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xml:base="https://metagame.hk/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Metagame | Full Feed</title>
    <link>https://metagame.hk/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://metagame.hk/feed/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Blog about photography, tech, gaming, coffee, travel, and personal productivity.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Google Zero, Small Web 1.0</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-08-04-google-zero-small-web-one/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s 2025. Internet is being flooded with AI slop and misinformation. Google doesn’t drive traffic anymore, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pewresearch.org/short-reads/2025/07/22/google-users-are-less-likely-to-click-on-links-when-an-ai-summary-appears-in-the-results/&quot;&gt;it keeps it for itself&lt;/a&gt; instead — with AI summaries and top results reserved exclusively for ads. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/11/27/musk-x-throttle-links-threads-bluesky/&quot;&gt;Social media throttle links&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a great environment to build a new website in. Building an audience is harder than ever. But maybe, &lt;em&gt;just maybe&lt;/em&gt; we can use this to our advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is value in independence from platforms and big tech. In maintaining a simple website that’s just files and folders — and not a database, scripts, and dynamic content. There is value in providing &lt;em&gt;a personal perspective on a personal website&lt;/em&gt; to a small group of readers. Not everything has to scale, not everything has to pursue infinite growth, not everything has to be ruthlessly monetized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe returning to the Web 1.0 formula — a collection of websites connected through hyperlinks instead of social graphs and algorithms — is the way to go for small creators like myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoy linking out to other bloggers and pointing my readers to things that I &lt;em&gt;found elsewhere&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;found interesting&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://joelchrono.xyz/blog/links-make-the-web-great/&quot;&gt;Links are great&lt;/a&gt;! It’s so much better to send you into a rabbit-hole with a context-relevant link rather than stuffing this website with AI slop and SEO-optimized word salads. That’s where &lt;em&gt;small web&lt;/em&gt; really shines. You can enjoy the process of discovery, feel a sense of wonder, and get lost in the web — it’s fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;METAGAME is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/24167865/google-zero-search-crash-housefresh-ai-overviews-traffic-data-audience&quot;&gt;Google Zero&lt;/a&gt; blog. I receive pretty much zero traffic from search engines (apart from a handful of people encountering &lt;a href=&quot;https://metagame.hk/posts/2024-09-29-leica-d-lux-8-as-a-travel-camera/&quot;&gt;my Leica D-Lux 8 post&lt;/a&gt; that way) and social media. My dream/goal/hope is that other websites and blogs that I value would eventually link to something interesting they found &lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;. That&#39;s how I want to build my audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cutting our ability to reach more people sucks. But this might be a blessining in disguise. By denying us traffic, Google has set us free. We can write for humans again and care not for the SEO crawlers (and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/news/695501/cloudflare-block-ai-crawlers-default&quot;&gt;block AI bots&lt;/a&gt;). Words once again flow from interest, values, and personality — not from a SEO manual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So go ahead, &lt;a href=&quot;https://metagame.hk/blogroll/&quot;&gt;explore my blogroll&lt;/a&gt;. On top of that, here are two more blogs I’ve discovered just this past week. Diving into their archives now:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bjhess.com&quot;&gt;Barry Hess&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://manuelmoreale.com&quot;&gt;Manuel “Manu” Moreale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 08:42:56 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-08-04-google-zero-small-web-one/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025-07-29 08:13</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-07-29-0813/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Apple Journal on OS 26 beta now lives in three different sync states between my iPad Pro, mini, and my iPhone. They refuse to reconcile, even after hours on Wi-Fi. Can’t believe this is the best a $3T company can come up with when tasked with designing a journaling app.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 08:13:50 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-07-29-0813/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple OS 26 Public Beta First Impressions</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-07-27-apple-os26-public-beta-impressions/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some quick thoughts after the weekend with Apple’s OS 26 public betas (primarily iPad OS). Here&#39;s a selection of new features, how they work, how some of them are broken, and where does it leave the OS as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Add Reminder&lt;/em&gt; quick action from the lock screen is a convenient addition. I already use it a lot, on my iPhone in particular. It will likely replace &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/remind-me-faster/id985555908&quot;&gt;Remind Me Faster&lt;/a&gt; for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/zPusSYW9r--1404.avif 1404w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/zPusSYW9r--1404.webp 1404w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/zPusSYW9r--1404.png&quot; alt=&quot;Quickly add new reminders from lock screen&quot; width=&quot;1404&quot; height=&quot;1316&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt; got some nice improvements, but it’s buggy. I was looking forward to finally trying it on the iPad. iPhone has never been a place for mindful reflection for me. Somehow, I need a keyboard or a pen(cil) for that. And now that the app is finally cross-platform, I can start seriously considering it for my everyday journaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thing is, it’s the buggiest Apple app I’ve seen on this beta:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Syncing journaling suggestions seems to happen only on Wi-Fi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sync seems broken in general. Changes, even entire entries don’t sync reliably across devices. That doesn’t inspire confidence to store my memories in &lt;em&gt;Apple Journal&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way it handles handwriting is just not good. Something’s wrong with the way it calculates the position of the “drawing” object as it goes all over the place when you change the device’s orientation, the app’s window width, or hide/reveal the sidebar. I have also seen &lt;a href=&quot;https://ljpuk.net/2025/07/23/giving-ipados-26-another-shot/&quot;&gt;reports of Apple Pencil input lag&lt;/a&gt;, but haven’t encountered it myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[edit: day later] Oh no, LJPUK was totally right. After putting more than a couple of lines of handwriting into &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt; everything slows down to a crawl. The Pencil becomes laggy and the whole app becomes unresponsive. If you were thinking of doing your handwritten &lt;em&gt;morning pages&lt;/em&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt; on the iPad — I&#39;m sorry to report, but it&#39;s totally unusable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can create new, separate journals now. But if you try to recategorize your old entries into one of those new ones you’ve just created, your selection will revert after a couple of minutes (syncing error?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The longer the entry gets, the more laggy the typing experience becomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it still doesn’t have &lt;em&gt;on this day&lt;/em&gt; — a feature which is critical for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/dzKmv63Vfj-3816.avif 3816w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/dzKmv63Vfj-3816.webp 3816w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/dzKmv63Vfj-3816.png&quot; alt=&quot;Journal on iPad OS 26&quot; width=&quot;3816&quot; height=&quot;2173&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now I have to choose between &lt;em&gt;Journal, Day One, and Obsidian&lt;/em&gt; for my daily journaling. It’s hard! — and the trade-offs are real: security, data portability/ownership, attachment handling, UX, etc. And moving &lt;em&gt;years&lt;/em&gt; of entries from one app to another is way harder than moving some to-do’s between productivity apps! I&#39;ll keep agonizing over this, I&#39;m sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than that, I noticed small bugs here and there but nothing major.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/wCa0A9aKdC-909.avif 909w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/wCa0A9aKdC-909.webp 909w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/wCa0A9aKdC-909.png&quot; alt=&quot;App Library on iPad OS 26&quot; width=&quot;909&quot; height=&quot;719&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;em&gt;WhatsApp is very happy to finally be available on the iPad. So eager to get noticed!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Liquid Glass&lt;/em&gt; is a miss for me. Some elements look nice, but it definitely does not achieve its goal of “interface just gets out of the way and leaves more room for your content”. If anything, it’s the opposite. It’s distracting. It’s like it’s shouting “hey, look at me and all the cool effects I can do!”. Yeah, light refractions are cool for the first 5 minutes, but then it would be nice to be able to read what’s on the buttons and panels. Liquid Glass makes it harder!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The switches between light and dark modes on the interface elements based on what’s behind it are also jarring. Things that were easily accessible before, now require additional taps (e.g., “all tabs” view in iOS Safari). Options are less visibile and more difficult to reach. That&#39;s not what I expect from a well-thought-out UI!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No. It’s making my devices look more toy-like and harder to use at the same time. Form over function at its “finest”. That&#39;s very bad!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Safari&lt;/em&gt; looks awful on some websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/V_BpqQzdGF-2860.avif 2860w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/V_BpqQzdGF-2860.webp 2860w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/V_BpqQzdGF-2860.png&quot; alt=&quot;Safari in iPad OS 26&quot; width=&quot;2860&quot; height=&quot;1280&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Certain designs don&#39;t gel well with Safari&#39;s Liquid Glass. Notice the transition from glassy-transparent to almost-opaque to actual content at the top. I don&#39;t love it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;App icons look straight bad on some backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m still getting used to the new windowing system on the iPad. I like how with Stage Manager I can create separate spaces (e.g. a separate three-column view with all my social media), but now the &lt;em&gt;stages&lt;/em&gt; peek out from the edge of the screen (if you’re in a full-screen app like YouTube) all the time. That is distracting (and unnecessary?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/Ivu2JcYcF4-3576.avif 3576w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/Ivu2JcYcF4-3576.webp 3576w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/Ivu2JcYcF4-3576.png&quot; alt=&quot;Stage Manager in iPad OS 26&quot; width=&quot;3576&quot; height=&quot;2896&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Notice the slivers of white to the left. They&#39;re tiny but visible enough to be distracting and annoying.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like that &lt;em&gt;Command+Shift+/&lt;/em&gt; keyboard shortcut works with the new menu bar on the iPad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haven&#39;t tried the LLM model action in Shortcuts yet. Looking for a good use case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I don&#39;t think I like where Apple is going with this. There are a few nice conveniences, but the new design language doesn&#39;t work for me, and features both new and old seem very buggy (yes, even for a beta). Here&#39;s to hoping that things improve before official release.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 18:12:56 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-07-27-apple-os26-public-beta-impressions/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025-07-20 16:03</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-07-20-1603/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Using the typhoon day in Hong Kong (T10!) to make some updates to my blog. POSSE and privacy explainers are up, so is a new blog post! Please check it out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 16:03:50 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-07-20-1603/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Struggling With Gaming FOMO</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-07-20-gaming-fomo/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve just finished &lt;em&gt;Death Stranding 2&lt;/em&gt;. Sadly, I could not enjoy it. I could not experience it the way it wanted me to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/DgdUSilRth-1920.avif 1920w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/DgdUSilRth-1920.webp 1920w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/DgdUSilRth-1920.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;End of game summary&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making deliveries and deliberately traversing through the challenging landscape while accompanied by a brooding soundtrack — thats’s a perfect set up for a slow, cerebral, and meditative journey. And yet, I could never get into that rhythm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t think it’s game’s fault. Yes, it’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://thisweekinvideogames.com/review/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach/&quot;&gt;not as good as the first one&lt;/a&gt;, but it is still excellent. (It’s also an acquired taste, Hideo Kojima with his style, mannerisms, etc. — so don’t take my “excellent” for a recommendation!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, the problem was me. I was rushing to finish it. To reach the end credits before I get spoiled by some rogue social media post or some off-hand remark in a video review. To clear the way for the next big release (there are so many games coming out!) To make sure I still have time to catch up on podcasts, tv shows, and all the other pointless stuff that for some reason I want to be up-to-date with. (Why?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve put myself on a treadmill where everything feels rushed, everything feels urgent yet superficial, all the joy is being sucked out by FOMO, the backlog is looming, and spending too much time on one thing feels like a waste of time. Imagine that! Taking your time to savor things and enjoy them &lt;em&gt;feels wrong&lt;/em&gt;. What? How does that make sense?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did this to myself. I made my hobby into another to-do list to check off, another inbox to get to zero. How do I undo it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I want my hobby back&lt;/strong&gt;, I want to be able to enjoy it again. And to do that, I need to step off this damn treadmill and give myself time to immerse myself in the experience. And I know it may sound funny because — you know, I’m talking about &lt;em&gt;video games&lt;/em&gt;, something many still consider a waste of time in itself and not a &lt;em&gt;serious hobby&lt;/em&gt;. But it’s something that has been a part of my identity for 20+ years now. It’s important to me. Losing it is like losing a part of myself. It hurts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To reclaim my joy I need to take a long, honest look at my behaviors and attitudes. There are adjustments I definitely need to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Less social media and YouTube.&lt;/strong&gt; I really don’t need to be up to date on the newest or upcoming releases and their reviews. Playing games that are &lt;em&gt;in the news&lt;/em&gt; gives me a false sense of community and belonging. I’m doing what others are doing! Except, I don’t engage with them. I just silently follow the trend. I don’t participate in the discourse, I’m just a statistic in the view count or sales chart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trust my own gut over reviews.&lt;/strong&gt; I need to recognize that I get influenced by reviews &lt;em&gt;too much&lt;/em&gt;. I will try out a game that’s well-reviewed even if &lt;em&gt;deep down&lt;/em&gt; I know it will not work for me (either because of the genre, art style, story, or whatever). I take it too far and play some games out of obligation — and then blame myself for not having a good time (everyone else seems to be enjoying it — why can’t I?) This is not a healthy mindset and it needs to stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setting limits.&lt;/strong&gt; Would setting a gaming budget or some arbitrary limit on the number of games I can purchase each year… would that be helpful?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deeper reflection.&lt;/strong&gt; In my journal or Obsidian entries about games I play/finish, I need to go beyond just giving it a rating and writing a mini-review. I should try asking more questions, like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did you rush it? (Be honest…)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would you like to spend more time with it? Or has it run its course?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What worked for you and what didn’t? (Calibrate your gaming taste.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let curiosity guide me, not the clock&lt;/strong&gt;. Wander off, don’t rush the main quest just to get to the final cutscene. Let myself explore and find awe. I have my permission to take things slow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meta note: This entry would fit well in my journal but I don’t yet know how to feel about putting personal writing like this (I am describing a personal struggle) out on the blog. Let’s say it’s an experiment. This is me reaching out to people who feel the same way. Do you have similar struggles? — hey, we’re not alone! Have you figured it out? — please do share what helped you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading! —Chris&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 13:32:56 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-07-20-gaming-fomo/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025-07-12 16:03</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-07-12-1603/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Going back to tinkering with the blog after a series of unproductive personal life distractions. No new articles yet, but I put together a blogroll page today (blogging like it&#39;s 2015!) Rebuilding my own place on the web one step at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 16:03:50 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-07-12-1603/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Productively(?) Distracted</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-06-15-distracted/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/mZ_hdsFiYJ-2560.avif 2560w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/mZ_hdsFiYJ-2560.webp 2560w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/mZ_hdsFiYJ-2560.png&quot; alt=&quot;I use Arch, btw&quot; width=&quot;2560&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to admit that this whole &lt;a href=&quot;https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-04-this-is-the-year-of-linux-on-desktop/&quot;&gt;switching-to-Linux thing&lt;/a&gt; has been an elaborate distraction. Much like &lt;a href=&quot;https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-01-09-default-apps-for-2025/&quot;&gt;switching to-do apps&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://metagame.hk/posts/2023-05-23-my-new-way-of-taking-book-notes/&quot;&gt;note-taking systems&lt;/a&gt; before it — it’s just something to take me away from the scary reality of doing &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; work. Like writing this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a perfect excuse, really. Setting up your &lt;em&gt;productivity&lt;/em&gt; system is &lt;em&gt;being productive&lt;/em&gt;, right? — it’s right there in the name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then you find yourself in a constant state of getting ready to &lt;em&gt;do the thing&lt;/em&gt;. And you never actually get to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fool, with all his other faults, has this also, he is always getting ready to live. — Seneca, Letters from a Stoic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s not to say it’s been entirely pointless. I’ve discovered a whole new (to me) paradigm of using a computer. I learned (okay, more like &lt;em&gt;experienced&lt;/em&gt; rather than &lt;em&gt;learned&lt;/em&gt;) a new operating system, terminal commands; I successfully installed Arch Linux, broke and fixed countless things, and I watched it all burn. I wrote scripts to pull weather and air quality index from publicly-available APIs and automatically put it into my daily note in Obsidian every morning. I scripted other small useful utilities: a service to optimize new images in Obsidian’s attachments folder, and one to sort files in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.noodlesoft.com&quot;&gt;Hazel&lt;/a&gt;-like fashion. I found replacements for most of my daily-use software. I vibe-terminal-commanded myself into completely breaking my system and then set it up again. It was fun! And I learned a lot in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that’s part of the charm of Linux? There is no handholding. Instead, if you want to successfully install Steam and have it recognize all drivers (curse you, Nvidia!), &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.archlinux.org/title/Steam&quot;&gt;there’s a wiki page for that&lt;/a&gt;. Setting up your system means a lot Reddit browsing, googling, and AI-prompting to troubleshoot random stuff. It’s a lot of time spent trying to find a single post on some obscure forum where someone had a similar problem like you and managed to come up with a workaround. Jumping through hoops like that earns you nerd cred, but it costs a lot of time and frustration. (But once you figure it out, it’s so satisfying!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when I want to &lt;em&gt;do the thing&lt;/em&gt; instead of tinkering with the operating system, I’m back on the Mac (or iPad). It’s bland, sanitized, safe, and unfun — and not amount of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/os/macos/&quot;&gt;new shiny&lt;/a&gt; will change that —  but it gets out of the way and is not distracting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of &lt;em&gt;new shiny&lt;/em&gt;, the WWDC announcements were kind of &lt;em&gt;meh&lt;/em&gt;. The new design invokes no feelings whatsoever. But I am looking forward to seeing the updates to iPadOS in action. Did they finally figure out the tablet multi-tasking? (I’ve been fooled so many times, though!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway… If I were switching from Windows, I would have definitely stayed with Linux. Easy choice. It’s just so much better. No bloat, no upsells, it looks nicer, it’s more efficient, it does not spy on you, and it’s farther from US big tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Mac is… complicated. It does have upsells baked into the system, it is US big tech, it is trying too hard to pose as safe — but I have an efficient workflow here, it looks &lt;em&gt;fine&lt;/em&gt;, and it’s more elegant than Windows. Plus, the whole Apple ecosystem gives it an undeniable advantage, no matter how many open source app replacements I can find on Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So… enough messing with .conf files. Time to get to work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 15:22:47 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-06-15-distracted/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025-06-06 22:19</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-06-06-2219/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My Linux adventure has been so (surprisingly!) successful that I want to nuke my current setup and install Arch and Hyprland just so I can tinker with even more stuff 🧑🏻‍💻&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 22:19:50 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-06-06-2219/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025-05-22 17:47</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-22-1748/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From the mind behind the butterfly keyboard, here comes the OpenAI Pin!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 17:47:45 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-22-1748/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025-05-21 19:45</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-21-1945/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple Is Reinstating Fortnite to the App Store, and Because of the Malicious Compliance-Like Attitude That Apple Presents, App Store Policies Are Currently Under Scrutiny Around the World&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s an old adage in poker: If you look around the table and you can’t tell who &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glossary_of_poker_terms&quot;&gt;the fish&lt;/a&gt; is, that means you’re the fish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re surprised at how this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/news/668232/fortnite-ios-unavailable-worldwide-apple-epic&quot;&gt;malicious compliance stunt&lt;/a&gt; from Apple has turned out, especially if you’re a pundit who &lt;a href=&quot;https://daringfireball.net/linked/2025/05/16/fortnite-still-banned&quot;&gt;ran a piece&lt;/a&gt; applauding Apple’s stance as justified, then you are Tim Cook’s fish.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 19:45:14 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-21-1945/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>