<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xml:base="https://metagame.hk/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Metagame | Full Feed</title>
    <link>https://metagame.hk/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://metagame.hk/feed/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Blog about photography, tech, gaming, coffee, travel, and personal productivity.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Struggling With Gaming FOMO</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-07-20-gaming-fomo/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve just finished &lt;em&gt;Death Stranding 2&lt;/em&gt;. Sadly, I could not enjoy it. I could not experience it the way it wanted me to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/DgdUSilRth-1920.avif 1920w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/DgdUSilRth-1920.webp 1920w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/DgdUSilRth-1920.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;End of game summary&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making deliveries and deliberately traversing through the challenging landscape while accompanied by a brooding soundtrack — thats’s a perfect set up for a slow, cerebral, and meditative journey. And yet, I could never get into that rhythm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t think it’s game’s fault. Yes, it’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://thisweekinvideogames.com/review/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach/&quot;&gt;not as good as the first one&lt;/a&gt;, but it is still excellent. (It’s also an acquired taste, Hideo Kojima with his style, mannerisms, etc. — so don’t take my “excellent” for a recommendation!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, the problem was me. I was rushing to finish it. To reach the end credits before I get spoiled by some rogue social media post or some off-hand remark in a video review. To clear the way for the next big release (there are so many games coming out!) To make sure I still have time to catch up on podcasts, tv shows, and all the other pointless stuff that for some reason I want to be up-to-date with. (Why?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve put myself on a treadmill where everything feels rushed, everything feels urgent yet superficial, all the joy is being sucked out by FOMO, the backlog is looming, and spending too much time on one thing feels like a waste of time. Imagine that! Taking your time to savor things and enjoy them &lt;em&gt;feels wrong&lt;/em&gt;. What? How does that make sense?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did this to myself. I made my hobby into another to-do list to check off, another inbox to get to zero. How do I undo it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I want my hobby back&lt;/strong&gt;, I want to be able to enjoy it again. And to do that, I need to step off this damn treadmill and give myself time to immerse myself in the experience. And I know it may sound funny because — you know, I’m talking about &lt;em&gt;video games&lt;/em&gt;, something many still consider a waste of time in itself and not a &lt;em&gt;serious hobby&lt;/em&gt;. But it’s something that has been a part of my identity for 20+ years now. It’s important to me. Losing it is like losing a part of myself. It hurts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To reclaim my joy I need to take a long, honest look at my behaviors and attitudes. There are adjustments I definitely need to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Less social media and YouTube.&lt;/strong&gt; I really don’t need to be up to date on the newest or upcoming releases and their reviews. Playing games that are &lt;em&gt;in the news&lt;/em&gt; gives me a false sense of community and belonging. I’m doing what others are doing! Except, I don’t engage with them. I just silently follow the trend. I don’t participate in the discourse, I’m just a statistic in the view count or sales chart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trust my own gut over reviews.&lt;/strong&gt; I need to recognize that I get influenced by reviews &lt;em&gt;too much&lt;/em&gt;. I will try out a game that’s well-reviewed even if &lt;em&gt;deep down&lt;/em&gt; I know it will not work for me (either because of the genre, art style, story, or whatever). I take it too far and play some games out of obligation — and then blame myself for not having a good time (everyone else seems to be enjoying it — why can’t I?) This is not a healthy mindset and it needs to stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setting limits.&lt;/strong&gt; Would setting a gaming budget or some arbitrary limit on the number of games I can purchase each year… would that be helpful?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deeper reflection.&lt;/strong&gt; In my journal or Obsidian entries about games I play/finish, I need to go beyond just giving it a rating and writing a mini-review. I should try asking more questions, like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did you rush it? (Be honest…)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would you like to spend more time with it? Or has it run its course?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What worked for you and what didn’t? (Calibrate your gaming taste.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let curiosity guide me, not the clock&lt;/strong&gt;. Wander off, don’t rush the main quest just to get to the final cutscene. Let myself explore and find awe. I have my permission to take things slow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meta note: This entry would fit well in my journal but I don’t yet know how to feel about putting personal writing like this (I am describing a personal struggle) out on the blog. Let’s say it’s an experiment. This is me reaching out to people who feel the same way. Do you have similar struggles? — hey, we’re not alone! Have you figured it out? — please do share what helped you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading! —Chris&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 13:32:56 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-07-20-gaming-fomo/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025-07-12 16:03</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-07-12-1603/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Going back to tinkering with the blog after a series of unproductive personal life distractions. No new articles yet, but I put together a blogroll page today (blogging like it&#39;s 2015!) Rebuilding my own place on the web one step at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 16:03:50 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-07-12-1603/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Productively(?) Distracted</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-06-15-distracted/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/mZ_hdsFiYJ-2560.avif 2560w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/mZ_hdsFiYJ-2560.webp 2560w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/mZ_hdsFiYJ-2560.png&quot; alt=&quot;I use Arch, btw&quot; width=&quot;2560&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to admit that this whole &lt;a href=&quot;https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-04-this-is-the-year-of-linux-on-desktop/&quot;&gt;switching-to-Linux thing&lt;/a&gt; has been an elaborate distraction. Much like &lt;a href=&quot;https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-01-09-default-apps-for-2025/&quot;&gt;switching to-do apps&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://metagame.hk/posts/2023-05-23-my-new-way-of-taking-book-notes/&quot;&gt;note-taking systems&lt;/a&gt; before it — it’s just something to take me away from the scary reality of doing &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; work. Like writing this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a perfect excuse, really. Setting up your &lt;em&gt;productivity&lt;/em&gt; system is &lt;em&gt;being productive&lt;/em&gt;, right? — it’s right there in the name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then you find yourself in a constant state of getting ready to &lt;em&gt;do the thing&lt;/em&gt;. And you never actually get to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fool, with all his other faults, has this also, he is always getting ready to live. — Seneca, Letters from a Stoic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s not to say it’s been entirely pointless. I’ve discovered a whole new (to me) paradigm of using a computer. I learned (okay, more like &lt;em&gt;experienced&lt;/em&gt; rather than &lt;em&gt;learned&lt;/em&gt;) a new operating system, terminal commands; I successfully installed Arch Linux, broke and fixed countless things, and I watched it all burn. I wrote scripts to pull weather and air quality index from publicly-available APIs and automatically put it into my daily note in Obsidian every morning. I scripted other small useful utilities: a service to optimize new images in Obsidian’s attachments folder, and one to sort files in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.noodlesoft.com&quot;&gt;Hazel&lt;/a&gt;-like fashion. I found replacements for most of my daily-use software. I vibe-terminal-commanded myself into completely breaking my system and then set it up again. It was fun! And I learned a lot in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that’s part of the charm of Linux? There is no handholding. Instead, if you want to successfully install Steam and have it recognize all drivers (curse you, Nvidia!), &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.archlinux.org/title/Steam&quot;&gt;there’s a wiki page for that&lt;/a&gt;. Setting up your system means a lot Reddit browsing, googling, and AI-prompting to troubleshoot random stuff. It’s a lot of time spent trying to find a single post on some obscure forum where someone had a similar problem like you and managed to come up with a workaround. Jumping through hoops like that earns you nerd cred, but it costs a lot of time and frustration. (But once you figure it out, it’s so satisfying!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when I want to &lt;em&gt;do the thing&lt;/em&gt; instead of tinkering with the operating system, I’m back on the Mac (or iPad). It’s bland, sanitized, safe, and unfun — and not amount of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/os/macos/&quot;&gt;new shiny&lt;/a&gt; will change that —  but it gets out of the way and is not distracting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of &lt;em&gt;new shiny&lt;/em&gt;, the WWDC announcements were kind of &lt;em&gt;meh&lt;/em&gt;. The new design invokes no feelings whatsoever. But I am looking forward to seeing the updates to iPadOS in action. Did they finally figure out the tablet multi-tasking? (I’ve been fooled so many times, though!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway… If I were switching from Windows, I would have definitely stayed with Linux. Easy choice. It’s just so much better. No bloat, no upsells, it looks nicer, it’s more efficient, it does not spy on you, and it’s farther from US big tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Mac is… complicated. It does have upsells baked into the system, it is US big tech, it is trying too hard to pose as safe — but I have an efficient workflow here, it looks &lt;em&gt;fine&lt;/em&gt;, and it’s more elegant than Windows. Plus, the whole Apple ecosystem gives it an undeniable advantage, no matter how many open source app replacements I can find on Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So… enough messing with .conf files. Time to get to work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 15:22:47 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-06-15-distracted/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025-06-06 22:19</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-06-06-2219/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My Linux adventure has been so (surprisingly!) successful that I want to nuke my current setup and install Arch and Hyprland just so I can tinker with even more stuff 🧑🏻‍💻&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 22:19:50 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-06-06-2219/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025-05-22 17:47</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-22-1748/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From the mind behind the butterfly keyboard, here comes the OpenAI Pin!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 17:47:45 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-22-1748/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025-05-21 19:45</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-21-1945/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple Is Reinstating Fortnite to the App Store, and Because of the Malicious Compliance-Like Attitude That Apple Presents, App Store Policies Are Currently Under Scrutiny Around the World&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s an old adage in poker: If you look around the table and you can’t tell who &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glossary_of_poker_terms&quot;&gt;the fish&lt;/a&gt; is, that means you’re the fish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re surprised at how this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/news/668232/fortnite-ios-unavailable-worldwide-apple-epic&quot;&gt;malicious compliance stunt&lt;/a&gt; from Apple has turned out, especially if you’re a pundit who &lt;a href=&quot;https://daringfireball.net/linked/2025/05/16/fortnite-still-banned&quot;&gt;ran a piece&lt;/a&gt; applauding Apple’s stance as justified, then you are Tim Cook’s fish.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 19:45:14 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-21-1945/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here&#39;s What Helped Me Build This Blog With 11ty/Eleventy and GitHub Pages</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-20-personal-website-on-11ty-github-pages/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am finally happy with my website set-up. It’s not much — just some HTML, CSS, and a few templates — but it’s mine, I can configure it however I want, and I own it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been a journey, not gonna lie. Not everything worked out of the box, not for a website like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there are some things that official 11ty documentation doesn’t tell you. Let me save you the frustration and AI tokens. In this post I will go through the roadblocks I encountered — and how I&#39;ve cleared them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;First, principles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s begin with how I wanted to design Metagame. The choices here strongly influenced the solutions I used — and problems I faced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stephango.com/file-over-app&quot;&gt;File over app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. This website is just a bunch of files in folders. There is no platform, no store-bought template with inscrutable code, no Squarespace-like WYSIWYG. There is no lock-in. I’m not totally independent (I still need to host this page somewhere), but it&#39;s as close as I could reasonably get it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fast &amp;amp; lightweight&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s all static HTML, which should make it load quickly. There is no CMS and no database on someone’s platform that I need to query every time I want to navigate to a blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.citationneeded.news/posse/&quot;&gt;POSSE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. My content and my updates — they all start on my website and &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; get syndicated elsewhere. For me, Metagame is the center of my online presence. Everything I post starts here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simple code&lt;/strong&gt;. I&#39;m neither a programmer nor an app developer. I can work with basic code but don&#39;t talk to me about complex frameworks. Also, I don&#39;t mind vibe coding — as long as it returns something I can remotely understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy is not an afterthought&lt;/strong&gt;. You won’t see Google Analytics here. In the future, I may consider something like &lt;a href=&quot;https://plausible.io/for-bloggers-creators&quot;&gt;Plausible&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ability to develop the website locally and offline&lt;/strong&gt;. This is what primarily led me to 11ty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also wanted to &lt;strong&gt;escape US big tech&lt;/strong&gt;, but unfortunately both VS Code and GitHub are owned by Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, a super-important disclaimer: even though I&#39;ve developed a few websites before, I still consider myself a total beginner in this. I have not been keeping up with the current trends in web design, like at all. So please treat this as a record of a beginner stumbling his way through to solutions that are likely obvious (and/or even suboptimal) to veterans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, if your a beginner like myself, there&#39;s a good chance you will find something useful here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Problems and solutions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Permalink prefix for relative links&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the source code of my blog posts, all links are relative. Instead of pointing directly to a full URL (for example: &lt;code&gt;https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-11-a-different-relationship-with-tech/&lt;/code&gt;), they link to a relative path (like so: &lt;code&gt;/posts/2025-05-11-a-different-relationship-with-tech/&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This causes some issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I build locally, all is fine. But the second I deploy to GitHub Pages, stuff breaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I figured it was this: before custom domain, the page is hosted at the following address: &lt;code&gt;https://my_account_name.github.io/metagame/&lt;/code&gt;
But the relative link &lt;code&gt;/posts/2025-05-11-a-different-relationship-with-tech/&lt;/code&gt; tries to resolve to &lt;code&gt;https://my_account_name.github.io/posts/2025-05-11-a-different-relationship-with-tech/&lt;/code&gt; and not the correct one &lt;code&gt;https://my_account_name.github.io/metagame/posts/2025-05-11-a-different-relationship-with-tech/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently, here is a &lt;em&gt;native&lt;/em&gt; solution for this: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.11ty.dev/docs/config/#deploy-to-a-subdirectory-with-a-path-prefix&quot;&gt;--pathprefix&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.11ty.dev/docs/deployment/#mini-tutorials&quot;&gt;This is how you&#39;re supposed to use it&lt;/a&gt; when building on GitHub Pages. But for some reason it did not work for me. In the build, all links had multiple &lt;code&gt;/metagame/metagame/metagame/…&lt;/code&gt; folders inside them. For some reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But after some googling, I found &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/11ty/eleventy/discussions/2516#discussioncomment-11999750&quot;&gt;this script for relative links&lt;/a&gt;. It worked!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Setting up custom domain&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I manage my domain DNS record on Cloudflare. When setting up the integration between GitHub Pages and Cloudflare, I wish two things were more obvious:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That you have to add and verify your domain first in your general account setting (and not the repository settings).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.github.com/en/pages/configuring-a-custom-domain-for-your-github-pages-site/managing-a-custom-domain-for-your-github-pages-site&quot;&gt;official documentation&lt;/a&gt; is helpful, I just wish someone showed me a screenshot of what a correct configuration looks like. So here it is:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/HiDAfADRSY-1420.avif 1420w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/HiDAfADRSY-1420.webp 1420w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/HiDAfADRSY-1420.png&quot; alt=&quot;DNS set up in Cloudflare&quot; width=&quot;1420&quot; height=&quot;302&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Missing GitHub Pages Deploy Keys&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.11ty.dev/docs/deployment/#mini-tutorials&quot;&gt;mini-tutorial in 11ty docs&lt;/a&gt; had one crucial piece missing — it doesn&#39;t tell you that you need to generate GitHub security keys and where to put them. This gave me a lot of trouble as I did not know what was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lea-tortay.com/articles/github-pages-eleventy/&quot;&gt;this guide from Lėa Tortay&lt;/a&gt; did mention keys and got me started. Phew!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Eleventy-image causing super-long build times&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to do images right this time. Serve optimized versions, save bandwidth, make the website faster. Enter &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.11ty.dev/docs/plugins/image/&quot;&gt;eleventy-image&lt;/a&gt; plugin. It would automatically optimize images while building the website. Just what I needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was one hiccup, though. It was processing every image from scratch on every GitHub Pages build. That led to 5+ minute deploy times every time, even for such a small site like mine. Unacceptable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s what no-one told me: you have to point the eleventy-image output directory to .cache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;imageOptions.outputDir = &amp;quot;.cache/@11ty/img/&amp;quot;;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course! That makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Redirects&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My new blog has a different folder structure than what I had on Ghost (here posts are stored in ,&lt;code&gt;/posts/&lt;/code&gt;  folder; in Ghost they were all in the &lt;code&gt;root&lt;/code&gt; folder) — meaning permalinks to my blog posts would  — an inbound links would break. Fortunately, a redirect template can take care of that. Leave no broken link behind!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have the same problem, just &lt;a href=&quot;https://brianm.me/posts/eleventy-redirect-from/&quot;&gt;follow these instructions&lt;/a&gt; and you should be good to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, as far as I can remember, these were the biggest head-scratchers for me. Hope this saves you some time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other helpful resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The below have been hugely helpful in learning how all of this works:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.11ty.dev/docs/&quot;&gt;Official Get Started Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kzf9A9tkkl4&quot;&gt;6 Minutes to Build a Blog from Scratch with Eleventy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLtLXFsdHI8JTwScHvB924dY3PNwNJjjuW&quot;&gt;Eleventy Crash Course by Jaydan Urwin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lmnt.me/blog/how-to-make-a-damn-website.html&quot;&gt;How to Make a Damn Website&lt;/a&gt; was a good refresher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://rknight.me/&quot;&gt;Robb Knight’s blog&lt;/a&gt; was an inspiration for using 11ty and many blogging principles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/features/copilot&quot;&gt;GitHub AI Copilot in VS Code&lt;/a&gt; deserves a shout-out too. Things like the default two-column view on the front page or dark mode in style.css were all vibe-coded with a few prompts. As much of an AI skeptic that I am, I have to admint that this is a great use-case for AI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 19:58:47 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-20-personal-website-on-11ty-github-pages/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025-05-20 13:23</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-20-13-23/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This whole drama surrounding Marathon is more interesting than the game itself, to be honest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 13:23:19 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-20-13-23/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025-05-17 13:19</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-17-1319/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As an experiment in distancing myself away from US big tech, &lt;a href=&quot;https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-04-this-is-the-year-of-linux-on-desktop/&quot;&gt;I&#39;m trying out Linux&lt;/a&gt; on my laptop -- and it&#39;s surprisingly not-bad once you set it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar conclusion as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macstories.net/stories/the-ipads-sweet-solution/&quot;&gt;the one Federico Viticci arrived at&lt;/a&gt; -- since so many good apps these days are just web apps, the &amp;quot;switching cost&amp;quot; is not as high as it used to be!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 13:19:54 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-17-1319/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025-05-11 20:57</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-11-2057/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Want to make your iPhone into a dumbphone? Turn on Apple Intelligence. 🙃&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 20:57:47 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-11-2057/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>