<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xml:base="https://metagame.hk/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Metagame | Full Feed</title>
    <link>https://metagame.hk/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://metagame.hk/feed/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Blog about photography, tech, gaming, coffee, travel, and personal productivity.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>2025-05-20 13:23</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-20-13-23/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This whole drama surrounding Marathon is more interesting than the game itself, to be honest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 13:23:19 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-20-13-23/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025-05-17 13:19</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-17-1319/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As an experiment in distancing myself away from US big tech, &lt;a href=&quot;https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-04-this-is-the-year-of-linux-on-desktop/&quot;&gt;I&#39;m trying out Linux&lt;/a&gt; on my laptop -- and it&#39;s surprisingly not-bad once you set it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar conclusion as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macstories.net/stories/the-ipads-sweet-solution/&quot;&gt;the one Federico Viticci arrived at&lt;/a&gt; -- since so many good apps these days are just web apps, the &amp;quot;switching cost&amp;quot; is not as high as it used to be!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 13:19:54 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-17-1319/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025-05-11 20:57</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-11-2057/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Want to make your iPhone into a dumbphone? Turn on Apple Intelligence. 🙃&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 20:57:47 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-11-2057/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A different relationship with tech</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-11-a-different-relationship-with-tech/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My attitude towards &lt;em&gt;tech&lt;/em&gt; has changed considerably in the last five years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No longer am I optimistic about where things are going. No longer am I excited about the new technology advancements. Because what are they, really?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We made a slightly better phone this year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We made a &lt;a href=&quot;https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-04-03-a-lot-less-excited-about-nintendo-switch-2/&quot;&gt;slightly bigger and slightly more performant Switch&lt;/a&gt; than the last one.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great, thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thing is, the latest and greatest is not much greater than last year’s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was so &lt;a href=&quot;https://metagame.hk/posts/2024-09-13-iphone-13-pro-exit-interview/&quot;&gt;ready to replace my iPhone 13 Pro&lt;/a&gt; last year that I wrote it an eulogy — yet, ultimately I kept it for another year. 16 Pro was incredibly disappointing and I passed. A camera button and some half-baked “AI” features? Come on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m even thinking of skipping the 17s this year too. Just going to keep the 13 Pro until Apple finally releases a foldable. Hopefully next year! Now that would be something interesting — first time in a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it’s a larger phenomenon than just a new iPhone being uninspiring. Tech just &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P-TANCVoHlc&quot;&gt;isn’t fun anymore&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/ctM2TIXDFQs?si=lQd1XUx8ud5tHuvI&quot;&gt;Being online is tiring&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enshittification and monetization are sucking all the joy out of everything. Websites, services, apps, platforms, games — getting worse every year while becoming more expensive at the same time. Finding new ways to squeeze out revenue instead of finding new ways of making a better product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just how long can this go on? There must be a limit where a product just becomes completely unusable under the weight of all that bullshit. At some point we won’t have any more money to spend on subscriptions, loot boxes, battle passes, micro-transactions, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There must be a point where things finally break. When &lt;em&gt;people&lt;/em&gt; break and don’t accept this nonsense anymore. Am I there already? Maybe that’s why I’m so surprisingly open to &lt;a href=&quot;https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-04-this-is-the-year-of-linux-on-desktop/&quot;&gt;the idea of trying out Linux&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 09:20:16 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-11-a-different-relationship-with-tech/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025-05-10 21:40</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-10-2140/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;POSSE test 3. This short post should automatically publish from my blog into Mastodon, Bluesky, and Threads.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 21:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-10-2140/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025-05-10 10:21</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-10-1021/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think I have a working prototype of my static-HTML blog ready? It looks decent! Lightweight, just the essential stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I just need to go through the process of transfering my 30 blog posts from Ghost to here. Will be a while! I&#39;ll consider it my weekend project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 10:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-10-1021/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025-05-08 19:46</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-08-1946/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vibe-coding my way through setting up a static HTML blog on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.11ty.dev&quot;&gt;11ty&lt;/a&gt;. I have time until October to migrate away from Ghost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now how do I publish this on GitHub pages? Oh my!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 19:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-08-1946/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Is the Year of Linux on Desktop</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-04-this-is-the-year-of-linux-on-desktop/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a restless mind. I constantly look for ways to tinker with stuff. And once something works, I can&#39;t just leave it be and enjoy it. I have to move on to something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-03-31-is-apple-even-good-at-software/&quot;&gt;Last month&lt;/a&gt; it was (re-)introducing pen and paper to my note-taking system. Before that, it was the &lt;a href=&quot;https://metagame.hk/posts/2024-12-15-things-look-like-a-creative-goty/&quot;&gt;back-and-forth between Reminders and Things&lt;/a&gt; for my to-do system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you can imagine how dangerous &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/pVI_smLgTY0?si=BmXPv3MjrxTFV14Z&amp;amp;ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; is for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;s&gt;What’s stopping me right now is&lt;/s&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://frame.work/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;&lt;s&gt;Framework Laptops&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;s&gt;not shipping to Hong Kong…&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually installed Ubuntu on my gaming laptop today, alongside existing Windows 11 installation. Just to try it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m sure I won&#39;t get far. I&#39;ll probably encounter some insurmountable barrier and give up. I will inevitably bump into some jankiness, critical apps with outdated design (looking at you, Libre Office), or things simply not working (as I write this I struggle to make my external monitor to work!) I just hope that some big disappointment happens before I manage to spend any extra money to plug Linux into my workflow. Because I would have to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restart my 1Password subscription for a cross-platform password manager (currently with Apple Passwords)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move my email from iCloud back to Fastmail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable Obsidian sync, since my notes would no longer sync over iCloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find a new to-do app (Tick Tick looks like a decent candidate)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Probably subscribe to Spotify instead of Apple Music (or give YouTube Music another try?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming I stick with YouTube for #5, which at the moment doesn&#39;t cost me anything beyond what I&#39;m already paying, items 1-4 still add up to USD 215 per year. That is not insignificant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there&#39;s the cost of time required for setting everything up (though, let&#39;s be honest, that&#39;s the fun part) and moving my to-do&#39;s to some new app (switching mission-critical apps, assuming you even find a suitable replacement, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ljpuk.net/2025/05/04/tasks-out-of-sight-dont-get-done/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;can be a headache&lt;/a&gt;!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, there&#39;s the sunk/opportunity cost in under-using (or not using at all) the devices I already own, primarily my iPad Pro and Mac mini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when I think about that last one – it raises the biggest question of all. Linux would primarily replace MacOS for me. But then, Mac is the only platform Apple has not fully locked down yet. So why even try to escape it now? With Mac, I don&#39;t have the same frustrations Windows users have. There is less incentive to switch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I can do is to lay the groundwork for eventually leaving Apple&#39;s lock-in. A decision I&#39;m inching closer and closer to every time Apple does something greedy, malicious, or when it ingratiates itself with Trump. Which is very often these days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-04-this-is-the-year-of-linux-on-desktop/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025-05-08 12:00</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-04-1200/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 Is a Masterpiece.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since a piece of art enamored me so completely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m in love with this game. World, characters, story, visuals, gameplay, soundtrack — enchanting, captivating, unique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hype is real. Believe the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.metacritic.com/game/clair-obscur-expedition-33/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;high metacritic scores&lt;/a&gt;, trust all the positive reviews. This game is special. It deserves the reverence it’s been met with so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can sing its praises for many more paragraphs, but let me stop here. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedition33.com/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;Just go and play it&lt;/a&gt;. The less say about it the better — it’s best to go in blind.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-05-04-1200/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Lot Less Excited About Nintendo Switch 2 Than I Thought</title>
      <link>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-04-03-a-lot-less-excited-about-nintendo-switch-2/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/SiAa3Dr2YJ-1140.avif 1140w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/SiAa3Dr2YJ-1140.webp 1140w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://metagame.hk/img/built/SiAa3Dr2YJ-1140.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Nintendo Switch 2&quot; width=&quot;1140&quot; height=&quot;641&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Nintendo Switch 2 / Image: Nintendo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I genuinely wanted to be excited about &lt;strong&gt;Switch 2&lt;/strong&gt; (it was my most anticipated hardware announcement this year!), yet – if I&#39;m being honest with myself – it just looks like a bad buy for me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#39;ve barely touched my Switch OLED since I bought it. (A painful realization!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fromsoftware.jp/duskbloods/?ref=metagame.hk&quot;&gt;The Duskbloods&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; console-exclusive, that initially looked like it would scratch my &lt;em&gt;Bloodborne 2&lt;/em&gt; itch – turns out it&#39;s a PvPvE game! No, thanks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&#39;t have any strong feelings or nostalgia for &lt;em&gt;Donkey Kong, Mario Kart,&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Kirby&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything else, including &lt;em&gt;Hollow Knight: Silksong&lt;/em&gt;, will be available on PC, it will look A LOT better there, and I already have Steam Deck OLED to play those games on the go (and with OLED!)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hollow Knight&lt;/em&gt; with its art style in particular – I expect it to look much better on OLED compared to LCD.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other than that, the third party games looked really poor. I know Switch isn&#39;t about high-end specs and cutting-edge graphics, but that&#39;s really not an excuse for releasing a game that looks like &lt;em&gt;Pokemon Legends Z-A&lt;/em&gt; in 2025.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prices, both hardware and games, are high enough to give me pause.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaking of prices, the fact they’re charging for their equivalent of &lt;em&gt;Astro’s Playroom&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Aperture Desk Job&lt;/em&gt; is such an own goal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I expected something that would bring me back to the Switch — but last night&#39;s Nintendo Direct wasn&#39;t it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, whatever excitement I had about it initially is now fading. Maybe I was just hyped for an &lt;em&gt;idea&lt;/em&gt; of a shiny new thing. Once I set emotions aside, Switch 2 doesn&#39;t look like a device for me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Sobolewski</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://metagame.hk/posts/2025-04-03-a-lot-less-excited-about-nintendo-switch-2/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>